[
  {
    "question": "The International Date Line is located",
    "feedback": "At the 180°E/W meridian, or in the vicinity of this meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an aeronautical ground light?",
    "feedback": "12"
  },
  {
    "question": "You should follow a track due north taking account of a north westerly wind. The line connecting your last known position with the DR position represents",
    "feedback": "The estimated track"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft following an approach procedure, requiring an approximate descent gradient of 6.6%, descends with an average ground speed of 185 kt. What is the corresponding vertical speed (ft/min) required during the descent?",
    "feedback": "1220 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table.\nWhat is the UTC and date if it is 00:35 Standard Time (ST) in Samoa on the 30th August?(ignore daylight-saving time)",
    "feedback": "11:35, 29th August"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: For take-off an aircraft requires a headwind component  of at least 10 kt and has a cross-wind limitation of 35 kt.  The angle between the wind direction and the runway is 60°,  Calculate the minimum and maximum allowable wind speeds?",
    "feedback": "20 kt and 40 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum difference in distance when proceeding along the great circle between two positions, instead of the rhumb line, will occur:",
    "feedback": "on east-west tracks at high latitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight is to be made from 'A' 49°S 180°E/W to 'B' 58°S, 180°E/W. The distance in kilometres from 'A' to 'B' is approximately:",
    "feedback": "1000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 470 kt,\nTrue HDG = 317°\nW/V = 045°(T)/45kt\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "5°L - 470 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 16:12 UTC a pilot turns overhead KOK VOR/DME onto a heading of 327°(M) to track the 320° radial at a TAS of 140 kt and a calculated ground speed of 158 kt. The pilot takes a fix from KOK at 16:42, and is on the VOR radial 323° at 79.5 NM DME.\nIf the aircraft has been flown accurately on the selected heading and speed, and given the following conditions, what is the probable reason for the difference between the DR position and the fix at 16:42?\nForecast wind: 10025KTMagnetic variation: 0°",
    "feedback": "Less crosswind component than forecast"
  },
  {
    "question": "A useful method of a pilot resolving, during a visual flight, any uncertainty in the aircraft's position is to maintain visual contact with the ground and:",
    "feedback": "set heading towards a line feature such as a coastline, motorway, river, or railway"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 198 kt,\nHDG (°T) = 180,\nW/V = 359/25.\nCalculate the Track(°T) and  GS?",
    "feedback": "180 - 223 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR chart ED-4\nA pilot is planning a VFR flight from aerodrome Arnbruck EDNB (N49°08' E012°59') to aerodrome Hohenfels ETIH (N49°13' E011°50'), departing at midday.\nWhat options describes the best means of checking the ground speed?",
    "feedback": "The road A93, which crosses the track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an exceptionally high unlighted obstacle?",
    "feedback": "22"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Polar Stereographic chart, an aircraft is to fly from A (85°S 030°E) to B (85°S 050°W). What is the final straight track at B?",
    "feedback": "310°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following factors that determine the accuracy of a DR position:\n1) The flight time since the last postion update\n2) The accuracy of the forecasted wind\n3) The accuracy of the TAS\n4) The accuracy of the steered heading\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nFL250, \nOAT -15 ºC, \nTAS 250 kt.\n\nCalculate the Mach number:",
    "feedback": "0.40"
  },
  {
    "question": "The true course of the rhumb line connecting the positions A (60°S, 011°E) and B (60°S, 009°W) is 270°.\nCalculate the true course in A of the great circle that connects both positions:",
    "feedback": "261°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 400\nOAT = - 65°C\nM = 0.90\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "506 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The standard parallels of a Lambert's conical orthomorphic projection are 07°40'N and 38°20' N.\nThe constant of the cone for this chart is:",
    "feedback": "0.39"
  },
  {
    "question": "A \"day\" is by definition",
    "feedback": "The period elapsed between two successive transits of a heavenly body"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL290 is required to commence descent \nwhen 50 NM from a VOR and to cross that VOR at FL80. \nMean GS during descent is 271kt. \nWhat is the minimum rate of descent required?",
    "feedback": "1900 FT/MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: HDG 265° TAS 290 kt W/V 210°/35kt  Calculate track and ground speed:",
    "feedback": "271° and 272 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island is observed by weather radar to be 15° to the left. \nThe aircraft heading is 120°(M) and the magnetic variation 17°W. \nWhat is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island?",
    "feedback": "268°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft descends from FL 240 to FL 80 for the final approach.\nTrack = 070°\nCAS = 220 kt\nOAT = ISA -10°C\n\nThe average TAS in the descent is:",
    "feedback": "276 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a Lambert chart, with standard parallels at 31°N and 47°N, calculate the approximate value of the constant of the cone:",
    "feedback": "0.63"
  },
  {
    "question": "A correct definition of longitude is",
    "feedback": "the arc at equator between the Greenwich meridian and the meridian of the place, measured in degrees, minutes and seconds, named East or West"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 23Surface wind from the tower: 26030KT\nWhat is the HWC?",
    "feedback": "27 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS: 120 ktsATA X: 12:32 UTCETA Y: 12:47 UTCATA Y: 12:50 UTC\nWhat is ETA at Z?",
    "feedback": "13:02 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "For this question use GSPRM chart ED-4\nCalculate the approx. GS of the aircraft on a flight between the two observed fixes stated below.\n10:22 passing over Regensburg Oberhub EDNR (N49°08' E012°05')10:38 passing over Arnbruck EDNB (N49°08 E012°59')",
    "feedback": "135 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what is the magnetic bearing of the NDB from the aircraft?\nNDB position: N55°26' W005°42'Aircraft position: N56°00' W010°00'Variation at the NDB: 9°WVariation at the aircraft: 11°WGreat circle track, aircraft to NDB: 101.5°(T)",
    "feedback": "112.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 485 kt,\nTrue HDG = 226°,\nW/V = 110°(T)/95kt.\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "9°R - 533 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 200 kt,\nTrack (T) = 110°,\nW/V = 015/40kt.\nCalculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "099 - 199 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct when two vectors are added in order to give a resultant vector?",
    "feedback": "The tail of one vector is added to the head of the other vector"
  },
  {
    "question": "Directions are stated",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft overflies waypoint 1 at 10:37 UTC and is overhead waypoint 2 at 10:49 UTC. The measured distance on the chart between the two waypoints is 11.4 cm. If 1 cm on the chart represents 3.2 NM on the Earth, what groundspeed has been flown between the two waypoints?",
    "feedback": "182 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "For navigation a Polar Stereographic chart is used. \nThe straight line between A (75°00'.0N, 166°00'.0E) and B (78°00'.0N, 154°00'.0E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle of the rhumbline in B is 317°.\n\nCalculate the direction (°T) of the straight line in position A:",
    "feedback": "323°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is descending down a 12% slope whilst maintaining a GS of 540 kt. The rate of descent of the aircraft is approximately:",
    "feedback": "6500 FT/MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason for the occurrence of seasons on the earth is:",
    "feedback": "the inclination of the earth axis with regard to the plane of the ecliptic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nDistance 'A' to 'B' is 100 NM,\nFix obtained 40 NM along and 6 NM to the left of course.\nWhat heading alteration must be made to reach 'B'?",
    "feedback": "15° Right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue Heading = 090° \nTAS = 180 kt\nGS = 180 kt\nDrift 5° right\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "360° / 15 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates an NDB?",
    "feedback": "6"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is maintaining a 5.2% gradient is at 7 NM from the runway, on a flat terrain; its height is approximately:",
    "feedback": "2210 FT"
  },
  {
    "question": "An NDB is located at position N55º26, W005º42'. The variation at the NDB is 9ºW. The position of the aircraft is 56º00'N, 010º00'W. The variation at the aircraft's position is 11ºW. The initial TT of the great circle from the aircraft position to the NDB position is 101.5º. What is the Magnetic Bearing of the NDB from the aircraft?",
    "feedback": "112.5º"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying directly from A (55°N, 005°E) to B (45°N, 055°W). At a certain moment in time the True Track of the aircraft is 275°. The aircraft is on track and the track angle error is 0°.\n\nWhich statement about this situation is correct?",
    "feedback": "The aircraft is flying along the great circle from A to B and did not yet pass the vertex of this great circle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Maximum allowable tailwind component for landing 10 kt.  Planned runway 05 (047° magnetic).  The direction of the surface wind reported by ATIS 210°.  Variation is 17°E.  Calculate the maximum allowable windspeed that can  be accepted without exceeding the tailwind limit:",
    "feedback": "11 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the chart extract.\nAt 10:07 you make a note of your position over the intersection of highways A3 and A92 (N48°49.0' E012°56.3'). Consider the DR positions DR-5 to DR-8 shown on the chart. Given the following information, determine your DR position at 10:19.\nTAS: 120 ktWind: 07540 KTTrue Heading: 085°",
    "feedback": "DR-7 (N48°49.1' E013°21.0')"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sun's declination is",
    "feedback": "The sun's position relative to the plane of the Equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 155 kt,\nHDG (T) = 216°,\nW/V = 090/60kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "231 - 196 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "For this question use Student Manual Chart E(LO) 1A\n\nAn aircraft is flying from Inverness VORDME (N57°32.6' W004°02.5') to Aberdeen VORDME (N57°18.6' W002°16.0').\nAt 1000 UTC the fix of the aircraft is determined by VORDME Inverness: Radial 114, DME distance 20.5 NM.\nAt 1006 UTC the fix of the aircraft is determined by VORDME Aberdeen: Radial 294, DME distance 10.5 NM.\n\nWhat is the average GS of the aircraft between 1000 UTC and 1006 UTC?",
    "feedback": "280 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nAn aircraft is flying a track of 255°(M),\n2254 UTC, it crosses radial 360° from a VOR station, \n2300 UTC, it crosses radial 330° from the same station.\nAt 2300 UTC, the distance between the aircraft and the station is :",
    "feedback": "the same as it was at 2254 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 100. The QNH, given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 1500 ft is 990 hPa. OAT = 0°C. The elevation of the highest obstacle along the route is 5000 ft. Use 1hPa = 30 ft.\n\nCalculate the aircraft's clearance above the highest obstacle on this route (rounded off in hundreds of feet:",
    "feedback": "4500 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given true heading 066°, variation 4°W, drift angle 12°R, relative bearing to the station 070°. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the station?",
    "feedback": "316°"
  },
  {
    "question": "When dealing with heights and altitudes in international aviation, we use the following units:",
    "feedback": "Metre and Foot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:DME ISY: N55º41', W006º15'Aircraft position: N54º30' W005º00'\nFind the initial magnetic track from ISY to the position of the aircraft and determine the distance between both locations.",
    "feedback": "152º, 83 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the time is 1400 LMT at 90° West, it is:",
    "feedback": "1200 LMT at 120° West"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nDirect Mercator chart with a scale of 1 : 200 000 at equator;\nChart length from 'A' to 'B', in the vicinity of the equator, 11 cm.\nWhat is the approximate distance from 'A' to 'B'?",
    "feedback": "12 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 480 kt,\nHDG (°T) = 040°,\nW/V = 090/60kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "034 - 445 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a straight line is drawn on an aeronautical chart between any two positions, what will determine the true track along that line between the two positions?",
    "feedback": "The chart convergence between the two meridians"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the TAS exceeds the CAS by 20% at FL 100, the OAT should be",
    "feedback": "+15°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The True Track of the straight line at A (75°N 010°W) is 080°. What is the Grid Track when passing the meridian 050°E?",
    "feedback": "090°(G)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island appears 30° to the left of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading (MH) of 020° with the magnetic variation (VAR) 25°W?",
    "feedback": "145°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Your destination aerodrome in the Northern Hemisphere has a higher latitude than the departure aerodrome. To determine the shortest ground distance, a straight line is plotted between the departure and destination aerodromes. You plan to navigate the flight exactly over the plotted line, approximating the great circle. The destination is in a westerly direction.\nWhich of the following statements is correct with respect to this flight?",
    "feedback": "Due to Earth convergence, the track direction will continuously decrease during the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue Heading = 180° \nTAS = 500 kt\nW/V 225° / 100 kt\nCalculate the GS?",
    "feedback": "435 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 268 kt, M 0.82. What is the PA ?",
    "feedback": "37000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Standard time is",
    "feedback": "The time enforced by the legal authority to be used in a country or an area"
  },
  {
    "question": "Atmospheric refraction",
    "feedback": "Cause the Sunrise to occur earlier and the Sunset to occur later"
  },
  {
    "question": "The main reason that day and night,  throughout the year,  have different duration, is due to the:",
    "feedback": "inclination of the ecliptic to the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The fix of the aircraft position is determined by radials from three VOR stations. The measurements contain small random errors, known systematic errors and unknown systematic errors. The measured radials are corrected for known systematic errors and are plotted on a navigation chart. The result is shown in the figure.  What is the most probable position of the aircraft?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kts, the headwind component is 20 kts and the rate of climb is 1000 ft/min. Top of climb is FL100. At what distance from the airport will this be achieved?",
    "feedback": "10.3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The mean sun",
    "feedback": "Moves with constant speed along the celestial equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 35Surface wind from the tower: 02020KT\nWhat is the XWC?",
    "feedback": "10 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by \"Aphelion\"?",
    "feedback": "The point of the Earth's orbit furthest away from the Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: fuel flow 6.5 t/HR, specific gravity 0.80, mach number 0.68, OAT –30°C, headwind component 25 KT. What is the specific fuel consumption ?",
    "feedback": "16.7 kg / NM ground distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in Tokyo (35°39'N 139°50'E) and plans to fly to Anchorage (61°13'N 149°52'W). What is the arc-to-time difference between Tokyo and Anchorage?",
    "feedback": "4 hours 41 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the initial true course and distance between positions N5800 W01300 and N6600 E00200?",
    "feedback": "036° - 638 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the danger about power lines, when flying VFR over a snowy area?",
    "feedback": "Dangerous if crossing a valley, less dangerous when crossing a ridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "A rhumb line from a position 86°N 30°W has an initial track of 085°T.\nWhat is it?",
    "feedback": "A spiral to the North pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming the Earth being a perfect sphere",
    "feedback": "A 1 minute arc measured on the surface of the Earth will be equally long wherever it is measured"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:Planned track: 227º(T)TAS: 360 KTWV 110º(T) / 70 KT\nWhat is the heading and GS required?",
    "feedback": "Heading 216º(T), GS 395 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The track plot",
    "feedback": "Shows the path of the aircraft relative to the ground"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: FL310, M 0.76. What is the CAS ?",
    "feedback": "280 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an unlighted obstacle?",
    "feedback": "23"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time of sunrise and sunset expressed in LMT:",
    "feedback": "varies with the observer's latitude and the time of the year because of the earth axis' inclination with respect to the plane of its orbit"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the time is 2000 UTC, it is:",
    "feedback": "1400 LMT at 90° West"
  },
  {
    "question": "In producing chart projections, the following projection surfaces may be used:",
    "feedback": "Plane, Cylinder, Cone"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nHalf way between two reporting points the navigation log gives the following information:\nTAS 360 kt, \nW/V 330°/80kt, \nCompass heading 237°, \nDeviation on this heading -5°, \nVariation 19°W.\nWhat is the average ground speed for this leg?",
    "feedback": "403 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Lambert conformal conical projection, scale 1:1 234 000. Standard parallels 36°N and 60°N. A (53°N, 010°W), B (53°N, 020°W).\n\nThe distance on the map between position A and position B measured along the rhumb line is:",
    "feedback": "less than 54.19 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accuracy of the manually calculated DR position of an aircraft is, among other things, affected by:",
    "feedback": "the accuracy of the forecasted wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 95 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 480 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "5 HR 03 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 07Surface wind from the tower: 14025KT\nWhat is the HWC?",
    "feedback": "8 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line is drawn on a Lambert Conformal Conic chart between two positions of different longitude. The angular difference between the initial True Track and the final True Track of the line is equal to:",
    "feedback": "chart convergency"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: An aircraft is on final approach to runway 32R (322°); The wind velocity reported by the tower is 350°/20 kt.; TAS on approach is 95 kt.  In order to maintain the centre line, the aircraft's heading (°M) should be :",
    "feedback": "328°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nYou are on a bearing of 301°(M) from POLE HILL 112.1 POL (N53°44.6' W002°06.2') and on a bearing of 001°(M) from WALLASEY 114.1 (N53°23.5' W003°8.1'). What is your current position?",
    "feedback": "N54°05' W003°09'"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which occasions does the rhumb line track and the great circle track coincide on the surface of the earth?",
    "feedback": "On tracks directly north-south and on east-west tracks along the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 083°(M),\nSurface W/V 035/35kt.\nCalculate the effective headwind component?",
    "feedback": "24 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long is 25 Kilometres  at 6000N?",
    "feedback": "13,5 Nautical mile"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying on a magnetic heading (MH) of 185º and your location is in the northern hemisphere. The relative bearing of an NDB is indicated on your relative bearing indicator as 065º. What true bearing should be plotted from the beacon to the aircraft on a Lambert chart if the variation at the aircraft is 6ºE and the variation at the station is 4ºE and the chart convergence between the aircraft and the NDB is 8º?",
    "feedback": "068º"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which statement is the \"Mean Sun\" best described?",
    "feedback": "The mean sun is a fictitious sun coinciding each year with the apparent sun at the Spring Equinox and travelling along the celestial equator at uniform speed."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue HDG = 002°,\nTAS = 130 kt,\nTrack (T) = 353°,\nGS = 132 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "093/20kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The constant of the cone, which is also known as convergence factor, of a Lambert conformal conic chart is quoted as 0.78535.\nAt what latitude on the chart is earth convergency correctly represented?",
    "feedback": "51°45'"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart, a rhumb line appears as a:",
    "feedback": "straight line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) and the clock code technique, what is the crosswind component (to the nearest whole knot)?.\nGiven:\nRunway 32Surface wind (from the tower): 00520KTVariation 15°E",
    "feedback": "15 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:Planned track: 090º(T)TAS: 300 KTWV 120º(T) / 40 KT\nWhat is the heading and GS required?",
    "feedback": "Heading 094º(T), GS 264 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR chart ED-4\nA direct flight is planned between Scharding Suben LOLS (N48°24' E013°27') and Sonnen EDPS (N48°41' E013°42') aerodromes. The true track from LOLS to EDPS is (1) ...... and the distance is (2) ...... NM.",
    "feedback": "(1) 030°, (2) 19.5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct about the scale of a Lambert projection?",
    "feedback": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "The inclination of the earth's axis of rotation with the plane of the ecliptic.",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a period of a few days, it is observed that the sunrise occurs earlier every day. If the date is not around the equinoxes, a possible location of the observer is the ....",
    "feedback": "33°N Parallel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft in flight is required to find its position with two DME readings. Dublin DME (DUB, 53º30'N, 006º18'W) reads 38 NM, Belfast DME (BEL, 54º39'N, 006º13'W) reads 46 NM. The aircraft is on a heading of 270º with both readings increasing. Find its position:",
    "feedback": "54º00'N, 007º00'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "The compression factor of the earth",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rhumb line track from A (53°50'N, 006°55'E) to B (53°00'N, 015°40'E) is 099°.\n\nCalculate the initial True Track along the great circle:",
    "feedback": "096°"
  },
  {
    "question": "When wanting to check flight progress by observation of a single visual position line (.e.g. a canal) the latter must be:",
    "feedback": "more or less perpendicular to the track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the constant of the cone of a Lambert chart that has the parallel of origin at 30°N:",
    "feedback": "0.5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Thule VOR is located at (76°32'N 68°15'W). A Polar Stereographic chart with the grid aligned with the Greenwich meridian is to be used. The local variation is 75°W. Which grid track must be maintained to track radial 210(M) inbound?",
    "feedback": "023°(G)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Departure A (25°N, 175°W) on 7 January at 1423 LMT. Difference UTC and ST(a) is 11 hours.\nDestination B (15°N, 155°E). Difference UTC and ST(b) is 10 hours.\nDistance along the great circle between A and B is 1790 NM. Average head wind component is 19 kt, average TAS is 400 kt.\nCalculate time (Standard time) and date of arrival at B.",
    "feedback": "16:45 08/01"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 465 kt,\nTrack (T) = 007°,\nW/V = 300/80kt.\nCalculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "358 - 428 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nMaximum allowable crosswind component is 20 kt. \nRunway 06, RWY QDM 063°(M). \nWind direction 100°(M)\nCalculate the maximum allowable windspeed?",
    "feedback": "33 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the average groundspeed experienced between ALVIN and AMMAN?",
    "feedback": "107 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which vectors could be components of vector A?",
    "feedback": "4, 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nWhat facilities are to be found at N51°50'24\" W008°29'42\"?",
    "feedback": "Civil airport, VORDME, compulsory reporting point"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhat is the position of the aircraft, if the distance from Wallasey (WAL) VORDME is 108 NM, and the radial is 078º?(note: ignore slant range corrections)",
    "feedback": "53º46'N, 000º10'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a non-compulsory reporting point?",
    "feedback": "11"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an oblate spheroid representing the earth's shape:",
    "feedback": "1 minute of arc along the equator measures a greater distance than 1 minute of arc along the meridian at a latitude of 45°N/S."
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming zero wind, what distance will be covered by an aircraft descending 15000 FT with a TAS of 320 kt and maintaining a rate of descent of 3000 FT/MIN?",
    "feedback": "26.7 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the true bearing of point A from point B?",
    "feedback": "270º"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 0020 UTC an aircraft is crossing the 310° radial at 40 NM of a VOR/DME station.\nAt 0035 UTC the radial is 040° and DME distance is 40 NM.\nMagnetic variation is zero.\nThe true track and ground speed are :",
    "feedback": "085° - 226 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure.\nAn aircraft is flying from A to B over mountainous terrain at a constant altitude. Differences in QNH at the given locations are negligible. The terrain clearance will be the smallest overhead the ......",
    "feedback": "location 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue Track = 095°\nTAS = 160 kt\nTrue Heading = 087°\nGS = 130 kt\n\nCalculate W/V:",
    "feedback": "057°/36 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "When approaching the International Date Line from the East, you",
    "feedback": "Should be prepared to increase your date by 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft on radial 110° at a range of 120 NM from SAXAVORD VOR (N6050 W00050) is at position:",
    "feedback": "N6027 E00307"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two vectors are added and a resultant vector is produced. What needs to be known about the two vectors which are added?",
    "feedback": "The directions and magnitudes of both vectors"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fuel amount of 146 Imp Gal allows a endurance of 4 HR 26 Min. What is the corresponding fuel flow ?",
    "feedback": "39.5 US Gal / HR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the heading required and the groundspeed:\nRequired track: 230°(T)Wind velocity: 315°(T) / 45 ktTAS: 320 kt",
    "feedback": "HDG 238°(T), GS 312 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A visual check point:",
    "feedback": "is a distinct point which is easily visually identifiable on the terrain as well as on the chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Maintaining a groundspeed of 180 kt, an aircraft leaves position A (30°S 010°W) and flies the rhumb line tracks listed below. What are the coordinates of point E?\nA to B: 090° for 25 minutesB to C: 180° for 32 minutesC to D: 270° for 28 minutesD to E: 360° for 24 minutes",
    "feedback": "30°24'S 010°12'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the average magnetic course and distance between  INGO VOR (N6350 W01640) and Sumburg VOR (N5955 W 00115)?",
    "feedback": "131° - 494 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Standard time for some areas is listed in the Air Almanac as UTC + 13 instead of UTC -11. The reason for this is:",
    "feedback": "keeping the same date as the political and/or economical entity to which they belong"
  },
  {
    "question": "A good approximation of the shape of the earth is:",
    "feedback": "an ellipsoid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information from an Air Almanac, what is the Standard Time (ST) and date in country A, if it is 15:00 ST on 15th July in country B?\nStandard Time in country A: UTC +4 hoursStandard Time in country B: UTC -7 hours",
    "feedback": "02:00 ST 16th July"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Mercator chart has a scale at the equator = 1 : 3 704 000. \nWhat is the scale at latitude 60° S?",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 852 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of two factors together will influence the difference in distance between the rhumb line route and the great circle route between two positions?",
    "feedback": "Mean latitude and change of longitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "You crossed the international date line on an easterly heading during a 12-hour flight. Comparing departure and arrival times, the date will (1) .... and the LMT will (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) decrease by one day, (2) increase by 12 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\naircraft height 2500 FT,\nILS GP angle 3°.\nAt what approximate distance from THR can you expect to capture the GP?",
    "feedback": "8.3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Fuel flow 28 Imp Gal / HR, specific gravity 0.72, TAS 154 MPH.What is the specific range ?",
    "feedback": "1.46 NM air distance / kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "For 1 February the Air Almanac lists the following data: Latitude: 6600N Morning civil twilight: 0756 Sunrise: 0900 Sunset: 1528 Evening civil twilight: 1632 The duration of morning twilight at 6600N is",
    "feedback": "1 hour 4 minutes and starts at 0756 LMT"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the rate of descent (ROD) on an ILS approach with a 12 % glideslope. Information given:\nTAS: 100 ktWind component: +20 kt",
    "feedback": "1440 fpm"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"conversion angle\" is",
    "feedback": "The angular difference between the rhumb line and the great circle between two positions, measured at any of the positions"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying directly from A (30°S, 060°W) to B (25°S, 020°W). At a certain moment in time the True Track of the aircraft is 091°. The aircraft is on track and the track angle error is 0°.\n\nWhich statement about this situation is correct?",
    "feedback": "The aircraft is flying along the great circle from A to B and did not yet pass the vertex of this great circle"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart, apart from meridians and the Equator,  a great circle will be represented by a:",
    "feedback": "curve concave to the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"duration of twilight\"",
    "feedback": "Is generally longer in positions at high latitudes that in positions at lower latitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart has a constant of the cone of 0.80. \nA straight line course drawn on this chart from A (53°N 004°W) to B is 080° at A; course at B is 092°(T). \nWhat is the longitude of B?",
    "feedback": "011°E"
  },
  {
    "question": "The great circle distance between A (60°N 010°W) and B (60°N 010°E) is 597.7 NM. The difference between the great circle distance and the rhumb line distance between C (50°S 170°E) and D (50°s 170°W) is:",
    "feedback": "less than 2.3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The \"Equation of time\"",
    "feedback": "States the difference in time of  transit of the Mean sun and the Apparent sun any\nparticular day"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator chart, the scale:",
    "feedback": "varies as 1/cosine of latitude (1/cosine= secant)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:Planned track: 227º(T)TAS: 360 KTWV 110º(T) / 70 KT\nWhat is the heading and GS required?",
    "feedback": "Heading 216º(T), GS 395 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is making a VFR flight under freezing conditions after recent heavy snow fall. Which of the following landmarks will provide the most reliable reference?",
    "feedback": "A high tension power line"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Conic chart great circles that are not meridians are:",
    "feedback": "curves concave to the parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 370 with CAS = 300 kt. OAT = ISA - 4°C. The compressibility factor is 0.932.\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "515 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 290 kt,\nTrue HDG = 171°,\nW/V = 310°(T)/30kt\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "4°L - 314 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nDetermine the initial track and distance from A (N54º55', W004º05') to position B (N55º35', W005º26'):",
    "feedback": "Track 311º(T), 62 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An airline company has its headquarters at Schiphol (UTC +2 h). An aircraft takes off from Quito on 4th September ST at 22:30 (UTC -5 h) and flies to Lagos (UTC +3 h). Flight time is 11:14 h. What is the ST at the headquarters at the time of arrival of the aircraft?",
    "feedback": "5th September 16:44 ST"
  },
  {
    "question": "The countries having a standard time slow on UTC",
    "feedback": "Will generally be located at western longitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nPressure Altitude 29000 FT, \nOAT -55°C. \n\nCalculate the Density Altitude:",
    "feedback": "27500 FT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given :\nETA to cross a meridian is 2100 UTC\nGS is 441 kt  \nTAS is 491 kt \nAt 2010 UTC, ATC requests a speed reduction to cross the meridian at 2105 UTC.\nThe reduction to TAS will be approximately:",
    "feedback": "40 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Spring and autumn equinox are the moments at which the sun reaches:",
    "feedback": "a declination of 0°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line is drawn on an aeronautical chart and the true track between two positions at different latitudes on that line changes by 28°. What does that mean?",
    "feedback": "The chart meridians at the two positions converge with an angle of 28°"
  },
  {
    "question": "By daylight a pilot continues a flight passing position 3 and is heading to position 4. Which significant features will the pilot see when overhead position 3, assuming that the lookout is not obscured by clouds or fog?",
    "feedback": "Abeam (90°) on the right side there is a hill top of 542 m, at 1 km distance ahead there is a hill top of 484 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a chart a straight line is drawn between two points and has a length of 4.63 cm. What is the chart scale if the line represents 150 NM?",
    "feedback": "1 : 6 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 210°(M),\nSurface W/V 230°(M)/30kt. \nCalculate the cross-wind component?",
    "feedback": "10 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the TAS.\nAltitude: 27000 ftMach Number: M 0.86OAT: -45°C",
    "feedback": "505 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rhumb line track from A (53°50'N, 006°55'E) to B (53°00'N, 003°00'E) is 250°.\n\nCalculate the initial great circle track:",
    "feedback": "252°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which figure accurately represents the two components of Vector A?",
    "feedback": "Figure 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given true heading 256°, VAR 13°E, relative bearing to a station is 333°. The true bearing to the station is",
    "feedback": "229°"
  },
  {
    "question": "If you want to follow a constant true track value",
    "feedback": "You must fly a rhumb line"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a chart, the distance along a meridian between latitudes 45°N and 46°N is 6 cm. The scale of the chart is approximately:",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 850 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying VFR on a cloudless night with a full moon, what factor has to be considered when planning the route?",
    "feedback": "Colours will be difficult to identify"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nThe coordinates of the heliport at Issy les Moulineaux are:\nN48°50' E002°16.5'\nThe coordinates of the antipodes are :",
    "feedback": "S48°50' W177°43.5'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the track error angle:\nPlanned track: 252°(T)Actual heading: 252°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 3° right",
    "feedback": "3° right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 132 kt,\nHDG (T) = 053°,\nW/V = 205/15kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "050 - 145 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The prime meridian is",
    "feedback": "The meridian running through Greenwich, England"
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the compass heading with the following data:\nTH: 200°Magnetic variation: 10°W",
    "feedback": "206°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure.\nAn aircraft is flying from A to B over mountainous terrain at a constant altitude. Differences in QNH at the given locations are negligible. The terrain clearance will be the highest overhead the ......",
    "feedback": "location 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nFind the true track and distance from A (55º50'N, 001º50'W) to B (54º55'N, 004º33'W):",
    "feedback": "240ºT, 108 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nCourse 040°(T),\nTAS is 120 kt,\nWind speed 30 kt.\nMaximum drift angle will be obtained for a wind direction of:",
    "feedback": "130°"
  },
  {
    "question": "How much time does it take for the Mean Sun to move from meridian 14515E to meridian 02345W?",
    "feedback": "11 hours 16 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a VOR?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the chart extract.\nAt 11:08 your location is over the intersection of highways A3 and A92 (N48°49.0' E012°56.4'). Consider the DR positions DR-1 to DR-4 shown on the chart. Given the following information, determine your DR position at 11:20.\nTAS: 120 ktWind: 07540 KTTrue Heading: 085°",
    "feedback": "DR-4 (N48°49.1' E013°20.5')"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what latitudes in the Northern Hemisphere is it possible to experience high values of variation?",
    "feedback": "High latitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Two vectors with different magnitude.\nHow many vectors will result if both vectors are added?",
    "feedback": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about the parallel of origin of a conformal chart?",
    "feedback": "The parallel of origin is the parallel at which the scale reaches its minimum value"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 200. The QNH, given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 1300 ft is 998.2 hPa. OAT = -40°C. The elevation of the highest obstacle along the route is 8000 ft.\n\nCalculate the aircraft's approximate clearance above the highest obstacle on this route:",
    "feedback": "10500 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 01Surface wind from the tower: 31025KT\nWhat is the XWC?",
    "feedback": "25 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The planets move around the Sun",
    "feedback": "In elliptical orbits"
  },
  {
    "question": "If a night VFR flight navigates out of the studied route, what will be the risk?",
    "feedback": "The presence of obstacles in the area not studied before the flight"
  },
  {
    "question": "The circumference of the earth is approximately:",
    "feedback": "21600 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chart distance between meridians 10° apart at latitude 65° North is 3.75 inches. The chart scale at this latitude approximates:",
    "feedback": "1 : 5 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft approaches runway 24 of Ryan airfield. The tower gives a wind of 260°/26 kt. The magnetic variation is 12°E. According to the airport chart the direction of runway 24 is 238°.\n\nCalculate the head/tailwind component:",
    "feedback": "24 kt headwind"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 01Surface wind from the tower: 05020KT\nWhat is the HWC?",
    "feedback": "16 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nWaypoint X (53°N, 175°E)\nWaypoint Y (53°N, 175°W)\n\nCalculate the final great circle track at Y:",
    "feedback": "094°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on rhumb lines:",
    "feedback": "Most rhumb lines will run as spirals from the one pole to another"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on meridians:",
    "feedback": "The meridians are parallel only at equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue HDG = 307°,\nTAS = 230 kt,\nTrack (T) = 313°,\nGS = 210 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "260/30kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 270 kt,\nTrue HDG = 145°,\nActual wind = 205°(T)/30kt.\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "6°L - 256 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the highest latitude listed below at which the sun will reach an altitude of 90° above the horizon at some time during the year?",
    "feedback": "23°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the positions (00°N/S,  000°E/W)  and (00°N/S,  180°E/W) on the ellipsoid.  Which statement about the distances between these positions is correct?",
    "feedback": "The route via the North Pole is shorter than the route along the equator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table.\nAt what UTC time does the sunset occur on the 19th October 2017 at Bodø airport in Norway (67°16'N 014°22'E)?",
    "feedback": "15:17 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following, calculate the climb gradient (%):\nRate of climb: 740 ft/min.TAS: 200 ktHeadwind: 15 kt",
    "feedback": "4%"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a TACAN?",
    "feedback": "4"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a polar stereographic projection chart showing the South Pole, a straight line joins position A (70°S  065°E) to position B (70°S  025°W).\nThe true course on departure from position A is approximately:",
    "feedback": "225°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR Chart ED-4\nWhat is the true track and distance between Straubing EDMS (N48 54.0 E012.31.1) and Deggendorf EDMW (N48 49.8 E012 52.8)?",
    "feedback": "106°, 15 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the effect on the Mach number and TAS in an aircraft that is climbing with constant CAS?",
    "feedback": "Mach number increases; TAS increases"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:TALLA (TLA) VORDME (55º30'N, 003º21'W)TURNBERRY (TRN) VORDME (55º19'N, 004º47'W)Radials to aircraft position: 161º from TRN, 210º from TLA\nThe aircraft is heading towards the northwest and its position is approximately at:",
    "feedback": "54º30'N, 004º15'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to pressurization problems you are requested to descend with 1000 FT/MIN only from FL 120 down to FL 50 maintaining a CAS 200 KT.What descent profile will you follow at no wind conditions and standard temperature?",
    "feedback": "2.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator chart, the distance of 1 inch measured at the equator corresponds to 25 NM. Calculate the scale at 43°N latitude:",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 333 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSRPM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft is on radial 044° from Shannon VORDME (SHA, 52°43'N, 008°53'W) with a DME reading of 71. Find its position on the chart:",
    "feedback": "53°39'N, 007°40'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 472 kt,\nTrue HDG = 005°,\nW/V = 110°(T)/50kt.\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "6°L - 487 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which option describes the greatest potential threat for VFR navigation at night?",
    "feedback": "The aircraft height during an approach can be easily misjudged due to insufficient external visual cues"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a mechanical computer, calculate the required rate of descent from FL120 to FL050 in the following scenario:\nDistance: 25 NMWind component at FL120: 30 kt headwindWind component at FL050: 10 kt headwindCAS: 100 ktOAT: ISA -10°C",
    "feedback": "420 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the ground speed for the following situation, using a mechanical computer.\nTrack: 264°(T)TAS: 480 ktWind velocity: 190°(T)/50 kt",
    "feedback": "463 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 220 kt;\nMagnetic course = 212 º, \nW/V 160 º(M)/ 50kt,\nCalculate the GS?",
    "feedback": "186 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 375 kt,\nTrue HDG = 124°,\nW/V = 130°(T)/55kt.\nCalculate the true track and GS?",
    "feedback": "123 - 320 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The positions A (30°00'N 017°30'E) and B at longitude (30°00'N 023°30'E) are plotted on a Lambert chart with a constant of the cone of 0.5. A and B are connected by a straight line. The True Track measured at A is 088.5°.\n\nWhat is the True Track measured at B?",
    "feedback": "091.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what is a suitable altitude for turning to the final approach course?\nDistance to the threshold: 4 NMThreshold elevation: 700 ftApproach angle: 3°",
    "feedback": "1900 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transferring position lines",
    "feedback": "It is unnecessary to plot the lines of position in its original position before transferring them"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the result when vector 1 is added to vector 2?",
    "feedback": "Vector C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Route 'A' (44°N 026°E) to 'B' (46°N  024°E) forms an angle of 35° with longitude 026°E. Average magnetic variation between 'A' and 'B' is 3°E.\nWhat is the average magnetic course from 'A' to 'B'?",
    "feedback": "322°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nHDG 080°T\nTrack 090°T\nTAS = 250 kt\nGS 280 kt\n\nCalculate the cross wind component:",
    "feedback": "43 kt from the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "The UTC of sunrise on 6 December at WINNIPEG (Canada) (49°50'N  097°30'W) is:",
    "feedback": "1411"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: TAS = 270 kt, True HDG = 270°, Actual wind 205°(T)/30kt, Calculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "6R - 259kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A direct Mercator graticule is based on a projection that is :",
    "feedback": "cylindrical"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircaft is located on radial 189° and at a distance of 62 NM from MANCHESTER VORDME MCT (53°21'N 002°16'W). What are the corresponding coordinates of its position?",
    "feedback": "52°20'N 002°29'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot intends to fly a route from A to B, covering a distance of 80 NM and departing at 12:15. The flight is planned with a heading of 235°. After 40 NM and at 12:27 the aircraft is crossing a railroad track, which runs 90° to the flight track. At 12:37 the pilot should be 1 NM left of the track but is actually 3 NM to the right. Calculate the new heading to fly directly to position B, including the estimated time of arrival (ETA):",
    "feedback": "198°, 12:39"
  },
  {
    "question": "What may cause a difference between a DR position and a Fix?",
    "feedback": "The difference between the actual wind and the forecasted wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 1215 UTC LAJES VORTAC (38°46'N 027°05'W) RMI reads 178°, range 135 NM. Calculate the aircraft position at 1215 UTC:",
    "feedback": "40°55'N 027°55'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the length of the day is measured with reference to the passage of the apparent sun",
    "feedback": "The length of the day will vary in the course of the year"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhich of the following is a correct interpretation of the chart symbols at airfield Waterford (52º11'N, 007º05'W)?",
    "feedback": "Civil aerodrome, IFR, ILS and NDB"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transferring position lines",
    "feedback": "The lines of position are transferred at ground speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sun's declination is on a particular day 12.00 S. Midnight sun may this day be observed",
    "feedback": "South of 7800S"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nW/V at arrival aerodrome at 1000 ft AMSL is 230°/15kt, W/V at TOD at FL 130 is 280°/45kt. Average track after TOD is 220°. ISA conditions. Descent speed IAS = 170 kt.\n\nFind the GS during the descent:",
    "feedback": "163 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the approximate distance from Dublin (53°29.0'N, 006°15.3'W) to a waypoint 20 NM north of Bremen airport. The coordinates of Bremen airport are (53°09.0'N, 008°45.0'E):",
    "feedback": "535.7 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the points A (10°S 10°W) and B (10°N 10°E). Which formula gives the Earth convergence between these two positions? (Convergency = change in)",
    "feedback": "Longitude (20°) x sin (0°)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The True Track of the straight line at A is 060°. When passing the meridian 100°E, the True Track is 090°. The Grid Track of this route on the chart is:",
    "feedback": "350°(G)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The total length of the 53°N parallel of latitude on a direct Mercator chart is 133 cm. What is the approximate scale of the chart at latitude 30°S?",
    "feedback": "1 : 26 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the scale vary in a Direct Mercator chart?",
    "feedback": "The scale increases with increasing distance from the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal conic chart the convergence of the meridians:",
    "feedback": "is the same as earth convergency at the parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "The difference of longitude is 139°15'. Calculate the corresponding time difference:",
    "feedback": "9 hrs 17 min"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft descends from flight level 180 to ground level with a constant TAS of 220 kt. The TT in descent is 080°. In the table the W/V at various flight levels in the area are given.\n\nCalculate the average GS in descent:",
    "feedback": "259 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table: An aircraft takes off from Guam at 2300 Standard Time on 30 April local date. \nAfter a flight of 11 HR 15 MIN it lands at Los Angeles (California). \nWhat is the Standard Time and local date of arrival (assume summer time rules apply)?",
    "feedback": "1715 on 30 April"
  },
  {
    "question": "You expect to have a GS of 300 Kt.. At what latitude will you be able to fly around the Earth in 20 hours?",
    "feedback": "7352N/S"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrack = 355°\nTAS = 190 kt\nW/V 270°/25 kt\n\nAfter 30 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3,5 NM right of track and 4.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position.\n\nCalculate the actual wind:",
    "feedback": "254°/34 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nFind the chart distance and true track from Manchester (N53.4º, W002.3º) to POLE HILL.",
    "feedback": "24 NM, 13º"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given : A is N55° 000° B is N54° E010° The average true course of the great circle is 100°. The true course of the rhumbline at point A is:",
    "feedback": "100°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The length of a apparent solar day is not constant because",
    "feedback": "The Earth's speed of revolution in its orbit varies continuosly, due to the orbit being elliptical"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two places are situated on the same parallel in the southern hemisphere. The great circle, rhumb line and the straight line between these places are drawn on a Polar Stereographic Projection.\n\nWhich statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "The great circle is situated between the parallel and the straight line, because the concave side of the great circle is always pointed towards the pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "For this question use GSPRM, VFR Chart ED-4:\nAn aircraft is approaching airfield Mühldorf (EDMY, N48°16.8' E012°30.1') from the east on track 270°. The descent should be planned to arrive at an altitude of 3500 ft approximately abeam of airfield Altötting (EDMY, N48°13.0' E012°38.9'). \nAtmospheric conditions: ISATAS: 110 KTAverage wind: 300°(T)/16KTRate of descent: 500 ft/minCruising level: FL125\nCalculate the distance (NM) from Mühldorf to the top of descent (ToD):",
    "feedback": "35 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line from A (53°N 155°W) to B (53°N 170°E) is drawn on a Lambert Conformal conical chart with standard parallels at 50°N and 56°N.\n\nWhen passing the meridian 175°E, the True Track is:",
    "feedback": "260.0°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a group of lighted obstacles?",
    "feedback": "18"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the areas close to the magnetic poles compasses are not to any use in air navigation, mainly because",
    "feedback": "The horizontal component of the Earth's magnetic field is too weak"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement regarding the apparent Sun and the mean Sun is correct?",
    "feedback": "The apparent Sun is the visible Sun, the mean Sun is a fictitious Sun."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 140 kt,\nTrue HDG = 302°,\nW/V = 045°(T)/45kt\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "16°L - 156 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft starts to climb from 4000 ft to 8000 ft with a ground speed of 220 kt and with a constant rate of climb of 1500 ft/min. Given the following information, how long will it take to climb and what ground distance will be covered?\nAverage climb TAS: 240 ktWind at 8000 ft: 20045KTApproximate track during the climb: 250°T",
    "feedback": "2.67 min; 9.4 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using mental navigation, the local speed of sound may be found using the following equation:",
    "feedback": "LSS = 644 + 1,2 TATc"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 440 kt,\nHDG (T) = 349°\nW/V = 040/40kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "4L - 415 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a True Heading of 090° the aircraft experiences drift of 5°S. On a True Heading of 180° the aircraft experiences no drift. On both headings the TAS is 200 kt and it is assumed that the wind is the same.\n\nWhat is the experienced wind speed and direction?",
    "feedback": "360°/17 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:WATERFORD (WTD) 368 kHz, 52º11'N 007º05'WKERRY (KER) 334 kHz, 52º11'N 009º32'W\nCalculate the true track and distance from WTD to KER:",
    "feedback": "270º, 90 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the maximum Wind Correction Angle (WCA).\nTAS: 120 ktCrosswind component: 10 kt from the left",
    "feedback": "5° left"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 300 kt, M 0.76. What is the PA ?",
    "feedback": "28000 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "In its path around  the Sun, the axis of the Earth has an inclination",
    "feedback": "of 66º 33' with the plane of the path"
  },
  {
    "question": "The wind is blowing 45° from the left of your track at 50 kt. Using Mental Dead Reckoning (no aids allowed), what is the drift and Wind Correction Angle (WCA) it the TAS is 180 kt?",
    "feedback": "12.5° right, WCA -12.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nDetermine the initial track and distance from A (N54º38', W004º28') to position B (N55º18', W003º13'):",
    "feedback": "Track 50º(M), 57 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the length of one degree of longitude at latitude 60° South?",
    "feedback": "30 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tropic of capricorn is situated at:",
    "feedback": "23.5°S"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is cruising at FL310, where the wind is 25060KT. Forecast winds for the area of descent are listed below. The pilot plans to arrive at the initial approach fix at 3000 ft.\nFL240: 27040KTFL180: 30020KTFL100: 31005KTFL050: 02015KTFL020: 02015KT\nThe wind that the pilot should apply for his descent planning is:",
    "feedback": "30018KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 30°N parallel, variations in the duration of a daylight period will be greatest when the Sun is:",
    "feedback": "Over the Equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart with standard parallels at 54°N and 59°N is used for navigation.\nThe straight line between A (55°00.0'N, 165°00.0'E) and B (58°00.0'N, ??°??.?'E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle along the straight line at A is 301° and at B is 292°.\n\nCalculate the longitude of position B:",
    "feedback": "154°12.4'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aicraft flying a flight leg from A to B has deviated to the right of the planned track by 3 NM after 17 minutes. Given the following information, what is the average drift angle, using the 1 in 60 rule?\nDistance from A to B: 83 NMAverage GS: 108 kt",
    "feedback": "6°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about small circles?",
    "feedback": "The centre of small circles does not coincide with the centre of the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the convergency of any two meridians on the Earth change with varying latitude?",
    "feedback": "It changes as sine of latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are required to descend from FL 230 to FL 50 over a distance of 32 NM in 7 minutes.  What will the glideslope be when you expect WC-25 during the descent?",
    "feedback": "5,29°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kts, the headwind component is 20 kts and the rate of climb is 1000 ft/min. Top of climb is FL050. At what distance from the airport will this be achieved?",
    "feedback": "3.6 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given pressure altitude and wind direction/speed:\n0000 ft: 26025KT3000 ft: 26030KT6000 ft: 27035KT9000 ft: 27040KT12000 ft: 28050KT15000 ft: 28555KT18000 ft: 29055KT\nWhich of the following is the correct wind direction and speed used for a descent from FL180 to ground level?",
    "feedback": "27040KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 110. The QNH, given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 1500 ft is 1020 hPa. OAT = -10°C. The elevation of the highest obstacle along the route is 7000 ft. Use 1hPa = 30 ft.\n\nCalculate the aircraft's clearance above the highest obstacle on this route (rounded off in hundreds of feet:",
    "feedback": "4100 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft departs from position A (04°10' S  178°22'W) and flies northward following the meridian for 2950 NM. It then flies westward along the parallel of latitude for 382 NM to position B. \nThe coordinates of position B are?",
    "feedback": "45°00'N 172°38'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "You should follow a track due north taking account of a north westerly wind. The line connecting your last known position with the air position",
    "feedback": "Shows a north westerly direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "In international aviation the following units shall be used for horizontal distance:",
    "feedback": "Metres, Kilometres and Nautical miles"
  },
  {
    "question": "For this question use GSPRM chart ED-4\nAccording to the flight plan the flight time from Waypoint A to Waypoint B is 26 minutes 30 seconds. During the flight the pilot observes that Waypoint B is passed earlier than planned. What is the most probable reason for this?\nPlanning data:\nWaypoint A: Tower (N48°53' E012°59'), elevation 2918 ftWaypoint B: Freistadt VORDME (N48°26' E014°08')W/V taken from a wind chart at FL100: 07030KTHeight during the flight: 1000 ft AGLGS: 120 kt",
    "feedback": "The W/V for planning was taken from FL100, with less headwind in flight at 1000 ft AGL"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island is observed to be 30° to the right of the nose of the aircraft. The aircraft heading is 290°(M), variation 10°(E).\n\nThe bearing °(T) from the aircraft to the island is:",
    "feedback": "330"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft descends from flight level 180 to ground level. In the table the W/V at various flight levels in the area are given.\n\nWhich W/V should be used to solve descent problems, e.g. the calculation of the GS from TAS and the Track in descent?",
    "feedback": "270°/40 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft in the southern hemisphere receives a QDM of 220º from an NDB station. What is the bearing to be plotted on a Mercator chart from the Meridian passing through the NDB?\nVariation at the station is 19ºW, at the aircraft's position 5ºE, and the convergency between the station and the aircraft is 12º.",
    "feedback": "051º"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies a great circle track from 56° N 070° W to 62° N 110° E. \nThe total distance travelled is?",
    "feedback": "3720 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some standard times may differ from UTC by other times than whole hours, because",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The True Track of the straight line at A (75°S 010°W) is 080°. What is the Grid Track when passing the meridian of 050°E?",
    "feedback": "070°(G)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the Jeppesen GSPRM Training Route Manual - Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:SPY VORDME (52°32'N 004°50'E) 113.3. MHz\nWhat is the aircraft position on radial 305°/50 NM?",
    "feedback": "The correct answers are: 53°01'N 003°43'E, 53°01'N 004°17'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Route A (53°24'N, 015°54'E) to B (32°00'N, 052°51'W).\nDistance flight plan is 3150 NM, average GS is 450 kt.\nDifference between Standard Time A and UTC is 1 hour, difference between Standard Time B and UTC is 4 hours.\nEstimated Time of Arrival (ETA) B is 10:00 ST(b) on 5 August.\nCaluclate the Estimated Time of Departure (ETD) A, expressed in Standard Time A.",
    "feedback": "08:00 ST(a) 05/08"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a polar stereographic chart for the northern hemisphere the true course of a straight line at latitude 60°N and longitude 170°W is 315°.\nThe true course of the straight line at longitude 145°E is:",
    "feedback": "270°"
  },
  {
    "question": "For navigation a Polar Stereographic chart is used. \nThe straight line between A (75°00'.0N, 166°00'.0E) and B (78°00'.0N, 154°00'.0E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle of the rhumbline in B is 317°.\n\nCalculate the direction (°T) of the straight line in position B:",
    "feedback": "311°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true?",
    "feedback": "The declination of the sun and the latitude of the observer will affect the duration of civil twilight."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the relationship between air distance and ground distance with a headwind?",
    "feedback": "Air distance is greater than ground distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert's chart has standard parallels at 45°00'N and 58°00'N and chart edges at 39°00'N and 62°00'N. At which latitudes will the actual scale be equal to the quoted scale?",
    "feedback": "45°00'N and 58°00'N"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies from A to B, the ground distance is 75 NM. After 48 NM, the pilot notices a cross-track error of 4° to the right. In order to directly reach point B, by using the 1-in-60 rule, the pilot should change the heading by ....",
    "feedback": "10° to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a Lambert chart, with standard parallels at 31°N and 47°N, calculate the approximate value of the constant of the cone \"n\":",
    "feedback": "0.63"
  },
  {
    "question": "According Kepler’s Second Law the radius vector of the earth’s orbit...",
    "feedback": "sweeps out equal areas in equal times"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven the following magnetic bearing and range from POLE HILL POL VORDME (53°45'N 002°06'W), what is the aircraft's position?\nRadial: 325°Range: 30 NM\n(slant range corrections should be ignored)",
    "feedback": "54°09'N 002°35'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "What effect does the inclination of the Earth's spin axis have on the average daytime temperatures in January and July over inland areas of Country A (25°N) and Country B (25°S)?",
    "feedback": "Country A will be hotter than Country B in July and colder in January"
  },
  {
    "question": "A route is flown from (80°S 100°W) to (80°S 140°E). At 160°W the Grid Track (GT) and True Track (TT) on a Polar Stereographic chart with a grid orientated on the 180° meridian are respectively:",
    "feedback": "290°(G) and 270°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven the following bearing and range information obtained from TURNBERRY (TRN) VORDME (55°19'N 004°47'W). What is the aircraft's position?\nRadial: 310°Range: 38 NM(Slant range corrections shall be ignored)",
    "feedback": "55°42'N, 005°42'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Polar Stereographic projection is",
    "feedback": "A plane projection"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is following a true track of 048° at a constant TAS of 210 kt. \nThe wind velocity is 350° / 30 kt. \nThe GS and drift angle are:",
    "feedback": "192 kt,  7° right"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the convergency at 5000N between the meridians 10500W and 14500W on the earth?",
    "feedback": "30,6°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The great circle bearing of position B from position A in the Northern Hemisphere is 040°. If the Conversion Angle is 4°, what is the great circle bearing of A from B?",
    "feedback": "228°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A great circle is defined as",
    "feedback": "A circle on the surface of a sphere, whose plane is cutting through the centre of the sphere"
  },
  {
    "question": "265 US-GAL equals? (Specific gravity 0.80)",
    "feedback": "803 kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft climbs from an airport at an elevation of 3000 ft to the cruising altitude of 30000 ft. Given the following information, which wind vector should be used to plan the climb? Both, temperature and pressure correspond to ISA.\nW/VSurface: 20022KTFL050: 21025KTFL100: 23030KTFL180: 26050KTFL240: 29070KTFL300: 32080KTFL340: 35095KT",
    "feedback": "27560KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position 'A' to position 'B',\ndistance 250 NM at an average GS of 115 kt. It departs 'A' at 0900 UTC.\nAfter flying 75 NM along track from 'A', the aircraft is 1.5 MIN behind planned time.\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at 'B'?",
    "feedback": "1115 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a DME?",
    "feedback": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "What would be the best visual mark for a VFR flight on a warm summer day?",
    "feedback": "A large water reservoir"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nPosition NDB (55°10'N 012°55'E)\nDR Position (54°53'N 009°58'E)\nNDB on the RMI reads 090°\nMagnetic variation = 10°W\n\nThe position line has to be plotted on a Lambert Conformal chart with standard parallels at 40°N and 48°N. Calculate the direction (T) of the bearing to be plotted from the NDB.",
    "feedback": "262°"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart at latitude of 45°N, a certain length represents a distance of 90 NM on the earth. \nThe same length on the chart will represent on the earth, at latitude 30°N, a distance of :",
    "feedback": "110 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Local Mean Time LMT at 35°25'S 110°45'W if the Coordinated Universal Time UTC is 18:34 on September 4th?",
    "feedback": "11:11 on September 4th"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nA (56°N 145°E)\nB (57° N 165°W)\n\nWhat is the difference in longitude between A and B?",
    "feedback": "050°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average TAS climbing from 2000 ft up to FL 120 at standard temperatures, given a CAS 185 KT and QNH 1013 ?",
    "feedback": "210 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what approximate date is the earth furthest from the sun (aphelion)?",
    "feedback": "Beginning of July"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 450Tas = 505 ktOAT = ISA - 12°C\nCalculate the Mach number:",
    "feedback": "M 0.90"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator projection a straight line is drawn between A (40°N 050°W) and B (50°N 060°W). Calculate the angle between the straight line and the great circle in position A.",
    "feedback": "3.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the ground distance in km, on an ATS route between VORs, if the distance on the en-route chart measures 200 mm and the quoted scale is 1 inch = 20 NM",
    "feedback": "292 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Referring to the Earth's magnetic field,",
    "feedback": "The inclination is 90° at the magnetic poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the highest latitude listed below at which the sun will rise above the horizon and set every day?",
    "feedback": "64°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the aircraft's TAS.\nGS: 485 ktCruising level: FL340Wind component: 35 kt headwindOAT: ISA -15°C",
    "feedback": "520 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line is drawn on a polar stereographic chart from position A (75°N 060°E) to position B (75°N 060°W). What is the initial straight track?",
    "feedback": "330°"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying VFR by day in early summer over a part of central Europe, you have been busy looking at the scenery and not concentrating on where exactly you are. What are the features which would be suitable for you to set your heading towards, when unsure of your position?\n1) A motorway2) A junction of two small roads3) A railway4) A river5) A coastline6) A fruit farm",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using Mental Dead Reckoning (no aids allowed), determine the drift and Wind Correction Angle (WCA), given:\nTAS: 240 ktWind: blowing 30° from the right of your track at 60 kt",
    "feedback": "Drift 7.5 left, WCA + 7.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following factors influence the difference in duration between day and night at a particular location?\n1) Longitude of the location2) Latitude of the location3) Time of the year4) Location of the Moon in its orbit around the Earth5) Elevation of the location",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nMagnetic track = 210°,\nMagnetic HDG = 215°,\nVAR = 15°E,\nTAS = 360 kt,\nAircraft flies 64 NM in 12 MIN.\nCalculate the true W/V?",
    "feedback": "265°/50 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft has 75 NM (track) to go to the initial approach fix, at which it should be level at 7500 feet altitude. The aircraft is cleared to descend from the present altitude of 35000 feet.\nWhat descent gradient should be achieved?",
    "feedback": "6.1 %"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:\nCLYDE waypoint: N55°58' W004°48'INPIP waypoint: N54°53' W002°54'\nCalculate the true track from CLYDE to INPIP and the distance from CLYDE until reaching the latitude of N55°:",
    "feedback": "135°, 81 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal chart the distance between two parallels of latitude having a \ndifference of latitude = 2° , is measured to be 112 millimetres. The distance between two meridians, spaced 2°  longitude, is, according to the chart 70 NM.\nWhat is the latitude in the centre of the described square?",
    "feedback": "54°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot intends to fly a route from A to B, covering a distance of 80 NM and departing at 12:15. The flight is planned with a heading of 235°. After 40 NM and at 12:27 the aircraft is crossing a railroad track, which runs 90° to the flight track. At 12:33 the aircraft is located 4 NM left of the planned track. Calculate the new heading to fly directly to position B, including the estimated time of arrival (ETA):",
    "feedback": "251°, 12:39"
  },
  {
    "question": "A VOR is situated at positon (N55°26' W005°42'). The variation at the VOR is 9°W. The position of the aircraft is (N60°00'N W010°00'). The variation at the aircraft position is 11°W. The initial TT angle of the great circle from the aircraft position to the VOR is 101.5°.\n\nWhich radial is the aircraft on?",
    "feedback": "294"
  },
  {
    "question": "A route is drawn from (75°00'N 060°00'E) to (75°00'N 030°00'W) on a Polar Stereographic chart with the grid aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The Grid Track (GT) is:",
    "feedback": "255°(G)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, chart E(LO)2\nThe Lambert chart has standard parallels at 37°N and 65°N. An aircraft flying with a magnetic heading of 136° is over the dead reckoning position N55°00.0' W011°00.0'. In this position, the relative bearing obtained of Donegal NDB CFN (N55°02.6' W008°20.4') is 318°.\nWhat is the true bearing of the position line to be plotted from the NDB?",
    "feedback": "270°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nMach number .340\nPressure Altitude = 9000 ft\nOAT = ISA -15\n\nCalculate TAS:",
    "feedback": "212 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \ncourse required = 085° (T),\nForecast W/V 030/100kt,\nTAS = 470 kt,\nDistance = 265 NM.\nCalculate the true HDG and flight time?",
    "feedback": "075°, 39 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 390\nTAS = 440 kt\nOAT = ISA + 15°C\n\nCalculate the Mach number:",
    "feedback": "0.74"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following features are the most useful for VFR navigation by day?\n1) Tall masts2) Large lakes3) Streets in a large town4) Area with several small woods5) Active power station",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator projection a particular chart length is measured at 30°N. What earth distance will the same chart length be if measured at 60°N?",
    "feedback": "A smaller distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which definition of the equator is correct?",
    "feedback": "The equator is a great circle with its plane perpendicular to the earth rotational axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete line 2 of the 'FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG', positions 'C' to 'D'.\nWhat is the HDG°(M) and ETA?",
    "feedback": "HDG 193°  -  ETA 1239 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle between the true great-circle track and the true rhumb-line track joining the following points:  A (60° S  165° W)  B (60° S  177° E), at the place of departure A, is:",
    "feedback": "7.8°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The maximum difference between geocentric and geodetic latitude occurs at about:",
    "feedback": "45° North and South"
  },
  {
    "question": "A useful method of a pilot resolving, during a visual flight, any uncertainty in the aircraft's position is to maintain visual contact with the ground and:",
    "feedback": "set heading towards a line feature such as a coastline, motorway, river or railway"
  },
  {
    "question": "At mid- and high latitudes, the inclination of the Earth's spin axis in relation to the plane of rotation around the Sun is the cause of the variable amount of (1) .... and the changing duration of (2) .... throughout the year.",
    "feedback": "(1) insolation, (2) daylight"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements most accurately describes the appearance of parallels of latitude on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "Concentric circles around the pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 390\nOAT = ISA - 15°C\nCAS = 280 kt\n\nCalculate the TAS, assuming a compressibility factor of 0.93:",
    "feedback": "495 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the rhumb line track (°T) for the following route:\nOn a Lambert Conformal chart, a great circle track is depicted from A (N45°55' W070°51') to B (N46°032' W067°50').\nInitial depicted magnetic course: 104°(M)Magnetic variation at A: 18°WChart constant of the cone: 0.61",
    "feedback": "087°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at latitude 02°20'N tracks 180°(T) for 685 km.\nOn completion of the flight the latitude will be:",
    "feedback": "03°50'S"
  },
  {
    "question": "A small circle",
    "feedback": "Has a plane that do not pass through the centre of the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using Mental Dead Reckoning (no aids allowed), determine the drift and Wind Correction Angle (WCA), given:\nTAS: 140 ktWind: blowing 30° from the right of your track at 60 kt",
    "feedback": "Drift 13° left, WCA +13°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR chart ED-4\nA pilot is planning for a VFR cross-country flight from aerodrome Arnbruck EDNB (N49°07.5' E012°59.1') to aerodrome Vilshofen EDMV (N48°38.1' E013°11.7'), using visual checkpoints.\nWhat feature is situated at N48°40' E013°06'?",
    "feedback": "An unlighted/lighted man-made plant"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal chart the distance between two parallels of latitude having a  difference of latitude = 2° , is measured to be 112 millimetres. The distance between two meridians, spaced 2° longitude, is, according to the chart 70 NM. What is the scale of the chart, in the middle of the square described?",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 984 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nRunway direction 230°(T), \nSurface W/V 280°(T)/40 kt. \nCalculate the effective cross-wind component?",
    "feedback": "31 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A course of 120°(T) is drawn between 'X' (61°30'N) and 'Y' (58°30'N) on a Lambert Conformal conic chart with a scale of 1 : 1 000 000 at 60°N. \nThe chart distance between 'X' and 'Y' is:",
    "feedback": "66.7 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the vertex of a great circle is true?",
    "feedback": "In the vertex the great circle reaches its highest latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tropic of cancer is situated at:",
    "feedback": "23.5°N"
  },
  {
    "question": "A DR position is to be found",
    "feedback": "On the desired track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue HDG = 074°,\nTAS = 230 kt,\nTrack (T) = 066°,\nGS = 242 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "180/35kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL350 is required to commence descent \nwhen 85 NM from a VOR and to cross the VOR at FL80. \nThe mean GS for the descent is 340 kt. \nWhat is the minimum rate of descent required?",
    "feedback": "1800 FT/MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the local mean time, position 65°25'N 123°45'W at 2200 UTC?",
    "feedback": "1345"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Earth's spin axis is inclined to the plane of the ecliptic. What effect does that have on the duration of daylight at Cambridge (52°N 000°E) compared with that at La Palma in the Canary Islands (29°N 018°W) on the same day?\nCambridge will have (1) .... hours of daylight on the 1st July and (2) .... hours of daylight on the 1st January.",
    "feedback": "(1) more, (2) fewer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nMagnetic track = 315 º, \nHDG = 301 º(M),\nVAR = 5ºW,\nTAS = 225 kt, \nThe aircraft flies 50 NM in 12 MIN.\nCalculate the W/V(°T)?",
    "feedback": "190 º/63 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Chart with standard parallels at 40°N and 55°N, the initial track angle of an airway from point A (54°N 015°W) to Aalborg (57°N 010°E) is 068°(T).\nWhat will be the track of arrival at Aalborg?",
    "feedback": "086°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information from an Air Almanac, what is the daylight saving time and date in country B if the time and date in country A is 01:50 Standard Time (ST) on 20th June?\nST country A: UTC + 13 hoursST country B: UTC - 11 hours(Daylight saving time (ST+ 1 hour) is kept in country B from March to October)",
    "feedback": "02:50 19th June"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR Chart ED-4\nA pilot is planning a VFR flight from an Austrian aerodrome towards aerodrome Straubing EDMS in Southern Germany (48°54'05\"N 012°31'03\"E). The final flight leg of the VFR route begins at the lighted obstacle located North of Linz (48°23'05\" 014°15'18\"E) which has an elevation of 3038 ft and ends at the destination aerodrome.\nWhat is the average true track for the final flight leg?",
    "feedback": "294°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island appears 30° to the left of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading of 276° with the magnetic variation 12°W?",
    "feedback": "054°"
  },
  {
    "question": "You start from P (7000N 01500E) and fly westward along the parallel of latitude for 2 hours at ground speed 220 Kt. What is your position after two hours flight?",
    "feedback": "00626W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the true track and the ground speed using the following data:\nTrue heading: 254°TAS: 163 ktW/V 130/30\nTrue track and GS are:",
    "feedback": "True track 262°, GS 182 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 15th October, a pilot is departing from Auckland, New Zealand (37°00'S 174°47'E, position west of the International Date Line) to Honolulu, Hawaii, US (21°19'N 157°55'W, position east of the International Date Line) where LT = UTC -10 hours. When departing, the aircraft's master clock displays 08:15 UTC. After landing, the pilot records a flight time of 8 hours and 37 minutes. Which of the statements below is correct?",
    "feedback": "The aircraft arrives in Honolulu at 06:52 LT on the 15th October"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 390 with CAS = 254 kt. OAT = ISA - 4°C. The compressibility factor is 0.942.\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "465 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL390 is required to descend to cross a DME facility at FL70. Maximum rate of descent is 2500 FT/MIN, mean GS during descent is 248 kt. What is the minimum range from the DME at which descent should commence?",
    "feedback": "53 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:  SHA VOR (N52º43.3' W008º53.1') radial 205°, CRK VOR (N51º50.4' W008º29.7') radial 317°.\nWhat is the aircraft position?",
    "feedback": "N52º11N, 009º12'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\ntrue track 070°\nvariation 30°W\ndeviation +1°\ndrift 10°R\n\nCalculate the compass heading:",
    "feedback": "089°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the two largest scales from the options below:\n1) 1 : 5 000 0002) 1 inch: 50 km3) 1 / 1 000 0004) 1 : 500 005) 1 cm = 10 NM",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven the following bearing and range information obtained from DEN HELDER (HDR) VORDME (52º54'N, 004º46'E), what is the aircraft's position?(note: Slant range corrections should be ignored)\nRadial 012ºRange 75 NM",
    "feedback": "54º07'N, 005º12'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "300 NM represents 10 cm on a Direct Mercator chart at 10°N. What is the approximate scale at 30°N?",
    "feedback": "1 : 4 885 864"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which map projection is described as follows:\n-  Meridians are straight lines\n-  The scale varie with latitude\n-  Most rhumb lines are curved lines",
    "feedback": "A Lambert conformal or a Polar stereographic projection"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table.\nMurmansk, Russia (68°58'N 35°05'E):When is the end of the evening civil twilight on the 18th November in UTC?",
    "feedback": "12:56"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft takes off from airport A (N33°56' W118°24', UTC -7 hours) at 21:15 Standard Time on 17th February and after a total flight time of 15 hours and 25 minutes arrives at airport B (N22°18' E113°55', UTC +8 hours). What is the Standard Time (ST) and local date when arriving at airport B?",
    "feedback": "03:40 ST, 19th February"
  },
  {
    "question": "The poles on the surface of the earth may be defined as",
    "feedback": "The points where the earth's axis of rotation cuts the surface of the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a mechanical computer, determine the TAS. Given:\nCAS: 160 ktCruising level: FL260Temperature: ISA + 18°C",
    "feedback": "250 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line is drawn on a polar stereographic chart from position A (50°N 130°E) to position B (50°N 130°W). What is the initial track of the straight line?",
    "feedback": "040°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following describes the appearance of rhumb lines, except meridians, on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "Curves concave to the Pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many NM would an aircraft travel in 1 MIN 45 SEC if GS is 135 kt?",
    "feedback": "3.94"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Fuel flow 28 Imp Gal / HR, specific gravity 0.72, TAS 154 MPH.What is the specific fuel consumption ?",
    "feedback": "0.68 kg / NM air distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"departure\" used in navigation also have the following meaning",
    "feedback": "Distance in direction East/West, given in nautical miles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the average TAS during the descent:\nCruising altitude: FL130Target level: FL060Average CAS during descent: 130 ktTemperature conditions: ISA",
    "feedback": "150 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The times given for Sunrise, Sunset, Morning and Evening twilight in the Air Almanac",
    "feedback": "Are given in LMT"
  },
  {
    "question": "TT from A to B is 167°, and the distance is 140 NM. Variation is 12W at A and 14W at B\nYou flight-plan WCA 8L. When the remaining distance to B is 35 NM you find that your position is 5 NM right of the flight plan track. Since over A you have steered as flight planned. What change of heading is required at this time to bring you directly to B?",
    "feedback": "11° left"
  },
  {
    "question": "The air position",
    "feedback": "Shows where the aircraft would be as a result of its TAS and true heading if there were no wind"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to ICAO Annex 4 Aeronautical Charts (Appendix 3 Colour Guide) what colour is recommended for depicting contours?",
    "feedback": "Brown"
  },
  {
    "question": "Observed from a position on the surface of the Earth the heavenly bodies seems to",
    "feedback": "Move from East to West"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island appears 45° to the right of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading (MH) of 215° with the magnetic variation (VAR) 21°W?",
    "feedback": "059°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nvalue for the ellipticity of the Earth is 1/297. \nEarth's semi-major axis, as measured at the equator, equals 6378.4 km. \nWhat is the semi-minor axis (km) of the earth at the axis of the Poles?",
    "feedback": "6 356.9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nRunway direction 305°(M),\nSurface W/V 260°(M)/30 kt. \nCalculate the cross-wind component?",
    "feedback": "21 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table.\nHobart International Airport is located in the Standard Time (ST) zone of Tasmania, which is UTC +10 hours. What is the Standard Time (ST) of the end of Evening Civil Twilight at Hobart International Airport, Australia (42°50'S 147°31'E) on the 11th October 2017?",
    "feedback": "18:58 ST"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft following a standard instrument departure procedure, which requires a minimum climb gradient of 6%, climbs with a average TAS of 190 kt. A headwind component of 15 kt is experienced. What is the minimum vertical speed (ft/min) to be flown to comply with the minimum climb gradient requirements?",
    "feedback": "1100 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "A great circle on the earth running from the North Pole to the South Pole is called:",
    "feedback": "a meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "A fuel amount of 160 US Gal allows a endurance of 3 HR 10 Min with a light twin engine piston aircraft. What is the corresponding fuel flow per engine ?",
    "feedback": "25.3 US Gal / HR"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the longitude of a position 6 NM to the east of 58°42'N 094°00'W?",
    "feedback": "093°48.5'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nYou are on radial 053 from POLE HILL VORDME (53º44.6'N, 002º06.2'W) and your DME indicates a distance of 55 NM. What is the approximate position of your aircraft?",
    "feedback": "54º19N, 000º51'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the distance to touchdown when you are 670 ft QFE on a 3,2°  glideslope approach?",
    "feedback": "1,96 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using latitude and longitude for a place",
    "feedback": "The location on the earth's surface of this place is defined"
  },
  {
    "question": "For navigation a Polar Stereographic chart is used. The aircraft position is (70°N 035°E). An NDB station is located in position (70°N 050°E). Variation at the aircraft's position is 32°E, variation at the NDB is 60°E. Deviation is + 2°.\n\nThe direction of the LOP in the chart from the NDB with reference TN is:",
    "feedback": "278°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2:\nYou are 32 NM from TLA VOR/DME (55°30.0'N 003°21.2'W) and 54 NM from DCS DME (54°43.3'N 003°20.4'W), your heading is 100°T and both ranges are increasing.\nWhat is your position in latitude and longitude?",
    "feedback": "55°28'N 002°23'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would a great circle between 80°00'N 010°00'W and 80°00'N 020°00'W appear on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "A curve concave to the North Pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to the table:\nAn aircraft leaves New York, USA, for Hawaii, USA, on the 21st July 2018, at 21:20 Standard Time (ST). Assume daylight saving time applies, except for Hawaii. The flight time is 12 hours 50 minutes.\nWhat will be the Standard Time and date of arrival?",
    "feedback": "04:10 ST, 22nd July"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 296 kt, M 0.72, FL 260. What is the OAT ?",
    "feedback": "Is not defined"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct about the scale of a Polar Stereographic projection of the Northern polar area?",
    "feedback": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the north pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "The constant of the cone in a Lambert chart is 0.8666500. The angle between the north direction of the meridian in position A (65°00'N, 018°00'W) and the meridian of position B (75°00'N, 023°00'W) on the chart is:",
    "feedback": "4.3°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart AT(HI)5, or to the extract\nWhat are the average magnetic course and distance between  INGO VOR (N6350 W01640) and Sumburg VOR (N5955 W 00115)?",
    "feedback": "125° - 494 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nMach number .340\nPressure Altitude = 9000 ft\nOAT = ISA -15\n\nCalculate CAS:",
    "feedback": "191 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reason that the solar day lasts longer than the sidereal day is that",
    "feedback": "both the direction of rotation of the earth around its axis and its orbital rotation around the sun are the same."
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line on a Lambert Conformal Projection chart for normal flight planning purposes:",
    "feedback": "is approximately a Great Circle"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an aircraft flies with a groundspeed of 135 kt for 2 minutes and 24 seconds, what ground distance will be covered?",
    "feedback": "5.4 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "1 nautical mile equals",
    "feedback": "6076 feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the track error angle:\nPlanned track: 240°(T)Actual heading: 235°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 7° left",
    "feedback": "12° left"
  },
  {
    "question": "With reference to the figure, which of the given angles depicts the conversion angle?",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the figures most accurately represents the great circle route from A to B on a Lambert conformal conic chart?",
    "feedback": "Figure A"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are required to descend from FL 230 to FL 50 over a distance of 32 NM in 7 minutes. \nWhat is the required TAS when you expect WC-25 during the descent?",
    "feedback": "300 Kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 132 kt,\nTrue HDG = 257°\nW/V = 095°(T)/35kt.\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "4°R - 165 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "From Rakovnik (50°05.9'N 013°41.5'E) to Frankfurt FFM (50°05.9'N 008°38.3'E) the True Track of departure along the straight line is 272.0°.\n\nThe constant of the cone of this Lambert Conformal projection is:",
    "feedback": "0.79"
  },
  {
    "question": "Times of Sunrise and Sunset is in the Air Almanac only given for one particular time in every 24 hour period. These data are accurate",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "The earth is one of the planets which are all moving in elliptical orbits around the sun."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAircraft heading is 190°(M) and both DME distances are decreasing. Determine the aircraft's position, given:\nMARHAM TACAN MAM (N52°39' E000°33'E) DME 44 NMTRENT VORDME TNT (N53°03' W001°40') DME 62 NM",
    "feedback": "N53°19' E/W000°00'"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 325° and five minutes later on a relative bearing of 280°. The aircraft heading was 165°(M), variation 25°W, drift 10°Right and GS 360 kt. When the relative bearing was 280°, the distance and true bearing of the aircraft from the feature was:",
    "feedback": "30 NM  and  240°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the extract from ICAO Annex 4 - Aeronautical Charts, Appendix 2:\nWhich numbers refer to the symbols for a cliff and a mountain pass?",
    "feedback": "4, 11"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is planning a VFR flight close to controlled airspace. Due to airspace restrictions, part of the flight will be flown at low level. Compared to flying at a greater height above the ground, which of the following is a problem of navigation at low level that should be considered when planning the flight?",
    "feedback": "Visual range to the horizon is restricted at low level"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is climbing from 3000 ft to 8000 ft on a 3° path at an average GS of 210 kt. The altitude of 8000 ft will be reached in (1)........ and the ground distance covered will be (2)..............",
    "feedback": "(1) 4 minutes and 46 seconds; (2) 16.7 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The relationship between the Mean Sun's movement along the Equator and Mean time is",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": ".\nRefer to the table\nAt what UTC time is the end of the Evening Civil Twilight on the 12th October 2017 at Bodø airport in Norway (67°16'N 014°22'E)?",
    "feedback": "16:39 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeroplane is climbing with a constant TAS of 220 kt and a headwind of 40 kt. If the rate of climb is 1300 ft per minute, what climb gradient is achieved?",
    "feedback": "7.1 %"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Earth convergency between position A (25°15'N 010°25'W) and position B (25°15'N 005°20'E)?",
    "feedback": "6.72°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The difference between the initial true track of the great circle on the surface of the earth joining two positions A and B (of unequal northern latitude and eastern longitude) and the true track of arrival at B is equal to:",
    "feedback": "the earth convergency of the meridians at A and B"
  },
  {
    "question": "During an approach the Flight Management Display indicates the following values:\nHDG = 270°T\nGS = 220 kt\nW/V = 240°/20 kt\n\nWhat is the value of the cross wind component and track in this situation?",
    "feedback": "10 kt from the left and 273°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is climbing from an airport at Mean Sea Level to an altitude of 21000 ft. Determine the wind vector which should be used to plan the climb, given:\nSurface: 03015KTFL050: 05025KTFL100: 07030KTFL180: 09040KTFL240: 11050KT\nConditions: ISA",
    "feedback": "08035KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "What approximate descent angle is required for an aircraft to descend 13500 ft over a ground distance of 45 NM?",
    "feedback": "3°"
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to fly from position A (10°00'N, 030°00'W) to position B (30°00'N, 050°00'W), maintaining a constant true course, it is necessary to fly:",
    "feedback": "a rhumb line track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the ground distance in statute miles on an ATS route between two VORs if the distance on the enroute chart measures 137 mm and the quoted scale is 1 inch = 15 NM:",
    "feedback": "93 sm"
  },
  {
    "question": "For descent planning from FL120 to 3000 feet MSL, the ground distance available is 25 NM.\nCalculate the required gradient of descent:",
    "feedback": "6.0 %"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO) 2\nDetermine the true track and distance from NDB UW (55º55'N 003º30'W) to reporting point HAVEN (55º27'N 003º00'W):",
    "feedback": "32 NM, 147º"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which two months of the year is the difference between the transit of the Apparent Sun and Mean Sun across the Greenwich Meridian the greatest?",
    "feedback": "February and November"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island appears 30° to the right of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading (MH) of 355° with the magnetic variation (VAR) 15°E?",
    "feedback": "220°"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Grid convergence\"",
    "feedback": "Is the difference in direction between Grid North and True North"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft follows a great circle track as it travels between point A (48°N 120°E) and point B (51°N 111°E). How does the great circle track change from point A to point B?",
    "feedback": "It decreases by 7°"
  },
  {
    "question": "As a contingency against a total INS/IRS failure and in order to be able to continue navigating safely while flying in polar regions, the Flight Crew should, at regular intervals ......",
    "feedback": "plot the aircraft's position and the time on a polar stereographic chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "The direction of True North for any observer is:",
    "feedback": "the direction of the observer's meridian to the North Pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nPosition A 45°N, ?°E\nPosition B 45°N, 45°15'E\nDistance A-B = 280 NM\nB is to the East of A\nRequired: longitude of position A?",
    "feedback": "38°39'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on \"departure\":",
    "feedback": "As the latitude increases, the departure between two meridians decreases"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ICAO definition of ETA is the:",
    "feedback": "estimated time of arrival at destination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the aircraft's TAS.\nGS: 485 ktCruising level: FL340Wind component: 35 kt tailwindOAT: ISA -15°C",
    "feedback": "450 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Flight plan information: TT = 090°, GS = 150 kt, W/V =160°/30 kt.\n\nAfter 12 minutes of flying the aircraft is 1.5 NM right of track.\n\nThe track angle error (TAE) is:",
    "feedback": "3°R"
  },
  {
    "question": "On what route is the difference between the rhumb line and the great circle the greatest?",
    "feedback": "GH"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Nautical mile is defined as",
    "feedback": "The average length of a 1 minute arc of a meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "A chart has a scale of 1 inch = 20 NM. The distance between two points on the chart is 17 cm. Determine the Earth distance:",
    "feedback": "248 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR Chart ED-4\nWhat is the approximate true track and distance from Straubing EDMS (N48º54' E012º31') to Vilshofen (N48º38' E13º12')?",
    "feedback": "121º, 32 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a scale, expressed as ratio, of a VFR chart that has two positions 17 NM apart on the ground, 5 inches apart on the chart?",
    "feedback": "1:250 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about ST is true?",
    "feedback": "Standard Time is determined by the government of the appropriate state and does not necessarily follow the borders of 15° wide longitude zones"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhich feature is shown on the chart at position 55º02'N, 001º41'W?",
    "feedback": "Newcastle aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2:\nWhat is the initial track direction (°T) and distance (NM) from Point A (54°00'N 002°00'W) to Point B (53°00'N 004°00'W)?",
    "feedback": "231°(T) and 93 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the Mean Sun moves 121°30' along the Equator, that equals",
    "feedback": "8 hours 06 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the heading (T) and ground speed:\nTAS: 270 ktTrack: 260°(T)W/V: 27530KT",
    "feedback": "Heading 262°T, ground speed 241 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the factors named hereafter should be considered by the pilot when selecting landmarks as visual reference points?\n\n1) Possibility of identification\n2) Transmitted frequency\n3) Visibility\n4) Closeness to the track\n\nThe combination that regroups all of the correct statements is:",
    "feedback": "1, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The DR position represents",
    "feedback": "The estimated position taking account of the estimated TAS and wind condition"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what is the true bearing of the aircraft's position line from the NDB plotted on a Polar Stereographic chart?\nAircraft position: 70°N 035°ENDB position: 70°N 050°EVariation at the aircraft: 32°EVariation at the NDB: 60°EDeviation: +2°",
    "feedback": "278°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the definition of the Geodetic Longitude of a point on the surface of the Earth?",
    "feedback": "The angle in the equatorial plane between the line a that connects the Earth's center with the prime meridian and the line b that connects the center with the meridian on which the point lies"
  },
  {
    "question": "for this question use Jeppesen GSPRM chart AT(HI)5:\nWhat is the true initial great circle track from the Bjornoya NDB to your position (N74 00.0, E015 00.0), given that the initial great circle track to the beacon is 057°?",
    "feedback": "249°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where on a Direct Mercator projection is the chart convergency correct compared to the earth convergency?",
    "feedback": "At the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given magnetic heading 075°, variation 4°W, drift angle 12°R, relative bearing to the station 270°. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the station?",
    "feedback": "161°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft takes off at an aerodrome at sea level and climbs to its cruise altitude of FL120, considering ISA conditions. The CAS during the climb is 140 kt and the QNH is 1013 hPa. The TAS to be considered for dead reckoning during the climb is ....",
    "feedback": "160 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert chart has a coverage area between parallels 27°00'N and 43°00'N. Its standard parallels are at 42°00'N and 30°00'N. The parallel of origin should be ....",
    "feedback": "36°00'N"
  },
  {
    "question": "Construct the triangle of velocities on a piece of paper, showing the following data:\n\nTH 305, TAS 135 Kt, W/V 230/40, Period of time from 1130 to 1145.\nWhat is the track in this period of time?",
    "feedback": "322°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 485 kt,\nOAT = ISA +10°C,\nFL 410.\n\nCalculate the Mach Number:",
    "feedback": "0.825"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a given day, the sunrise occurs at different times at different latitudes due to the .....",
    "feedback": "inclination of the Earth's spin axis with the ecliptic"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal conic chart, the distance between parallels of latitude spaced the same number of degrees apart :",
    "feedback": "reduces between, and expands outside, the standard parallels"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator chart, at latitude 60°N, the distance measured between W002° and E008° is 20 cm. The scale of this chart at latitude 60°N is approximately:",
    "feedback": "1 : 2 780 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 350 with CAS = 300 kt. OAT = ISA + 4°C. The compressibility factor is 0.939.\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "509 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft in cruise is at position 52°30'N, 008°00'W. Find the corresponding QDR and distance from Shannon VORDME (SHA, 52°43'N, 008°53'W).",
    "feedback": "The correct answers are: 118°, 34 NM, 041°, 56 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flying from A to B (total distance 110 NM) departed from A at 09:55 UTC. The planned arrival time at B is 10:45 UTC. After 25 minutes of flight, the aircraft overflies waypoint C located 45 NM away from A.\nWhat groundspeed should be flown as from C in order to reach point B at the planned arrival time?",
    "feedback": "156 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 270 kt,\nTrack (T) = 260°,\nW/V = 275/30kt.\nCalculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "262 - 241 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft is on the intersection of QTE 285° from Waterford (52°11'N, 007°05'W) and radial 037° from Cork VOR (51°50'N, 008°30'W). Find its position:",
    "feedback": "52°19'N, 007°58'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator chart, a distance of 6.2 cm equals 248 NM on the Equator. At a latitude of 42°N 6.2 cm equals a real distance of:",
    "feedback": "341 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "An approximate equation for calculating the convergency between two meridians is",
    "feedback": "Convergency= dlong x sin mean lat."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements regarding polar stereographic charts is the most correct?",
    "feedback": "A great circle line is between the straight line and the rhumb line, and always concave to the pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the Wind Correction Angle (WCA).\nTrack: 135°(T)TAS: 120 ktCrosswind component: 21 kt from the left",
    "feedback": "-10.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angular difference, on a Lambert conformal conic chart, between the arrival and departure track is equal to:",
    "feedback": "map convergence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The flight log gives the following data : \"True track, Drift, True heading, Magnetic variation, Magnetic heading, Compass deviation, Compass heading\" The right solution, in the same order, is :",
    "feedback": "119°, 3°L, 122°, 2°E, 120°, +4°, 116°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is maintaining a heading of 255°M. At 1256 it is on the 360° Radial of a VOR. At 1300 it is on the 330° Radial of the same VOR. \nAssuming still air, its distance from the VOR at 1300 is:",
    "feedback": "The same as at 1256"
  },
  {
    "question": "When descending on a 3° path with an average rate of descent of 1600 ft/min. from 10000 ft to 2000 ft, you will cover a distance of (1) .... in (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) 27 NM, (2) 5 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 350\nOAT = - 40°C\nIAS = 280 kt\nInstrument and position error to be neglected\nCompressibility factor = 0.94\n\nCalculate the True Air Speed taking compressibility into account:",
    "feedback": "487 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line drawn on a chart measures 4.63 cm and represents 150 NM. \nThe chart scale is:",
    "feedback": "1 : 6 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies from A to B, the ground distance is 78 NM. After 48 NM, the pilot notices a cross-track error of 5° to the right. In order to directly reach point B, by using the 1-in-60 rule, the pilot should change the heading to the left by ....",
    "feedback": "13°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the tables below:\n\nThe GMT of Morning Civil Twilight at (66°48'N 095°26'W) on 27th of January is?",
    "feedback": "14:36 GMT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Lambert conformal conic projection has to be produced mathematically to:",
    "feedback": "Obtain conformality"
  },
  {
    "question": "True Track = 085°GS = 180 ktW/V =290/30Var = 4°E\nCalculate the Track Error Angle of the aircraft is 1.5 NM left of track after 12 minutes of flying.",
    "feedback": "2.5°L"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 485 kt,\nHDG (T) = 168°,\nW/V = 130/75kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "174 - 428 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying on a heading of 040° from point A to point B in a crosswind. Consider that the actual wind in-flight matches the wind used for the flight planning calculations.\nIf the applied WCA is 5° left, the aircraft's True Track will be (1) .... and its in-flight drift will be (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) 045°, (2) 5° right"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pilot of a light twin-engined aircraft has filled in the flight log correctly for a charter flight to Nice in France, with the fuel recorded in litres. What is the new estimate for fuel remaining at EBROX?",
    "feedback": "353 litres"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is planned to fly from position 'A' to position 'B',distance \n320 NM, at an average GS of 180 kt. It departs 'A' at 1200 UTC.\nAfter flying 70 NM along track from 'A', the aircraft is 3 MIN ahead of planned time.\nUsing the actual GS experienced, what is the revised ETA at 'B'?",
    "feedback": "1333 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following factors influence the duration of day and night at a location?\n1) The location's longitude2) The location's latitude3) The time of the year4) The location of the Moon in its orbit of the Earth5) The location's elevation",
    "feedback": "2, 3, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "The declination of the sun is defined as:",
    "feedback": "the angular distance of the sun north or south of the celestial equator."
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart AT(HI)5, or to the extract\nWhat are the average magnetic course and distance between position N6000 W02000 and Sumburgh VOR (N5955 W 00115)?",
    "feedback": "098° - 562 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft climbs from ground level to a cruising flight level of 180. In the table the W/V at various flight levels in the area are given.\n\nWhich W/V should be used to solve climb problems, e.g. the calculation of the GS from TAS and the Track in climb?",
    "feedback": "280°/50 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 60° N the scale of a direct Mercator chart is 1 : 3 000 000. What is the scale at the equator?",
    "feedback": "1 : 6 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the correct answer regarding sunrise and sunset times, considering a location in the Northern Hemisphere?",
    "feedback": "Sunrise and sunset times vary with latitude because of the tilt of the Earth's rotational axis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:  Compass Heading 090°,  Deviation 2°W,  Variation 12°E,  TAS 160 kt. Whilst maintaining a radial 070° from a VOR station,  the aircraft flies a ground distance of 14 NM in 6 MIN.  What is the W/V °(T)?",
    "feedback": "160°/50 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transferring range position lines, you should",
    "feedback": "Transfer the origin and plot the range position lines from the transferred origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nThe magnetic track between  N55°40.0' W004°14.7' and N54°52.6 W002°53.8' is:",
    "feedback": "139°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A nautical mile is equivalent to:",
    "feedback": "1852 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given two positions:  A (56°S, 010°W)  B (56°S, 030°W)\n\nWhich statement is true?",
    "feedback": "The departure between A and B is more than the great circle distance between A and B"
  },
  {
    "question": "After flying on the correct heading at the planned airspeed, the aircraft arrives abeam Wimereux at 14:42, but off the intended track. The pilot sees Wimereux approximately 1 NM to the left.\nWhat is the approximate wind experienced on this leg?",
    "feedback": "205°(T)/25 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue Track 239°\nTrue Heading 229°\nTAS 555 kt\nGS 577 kt\n\nCalculate the wind velocity;",
    "feedback": "130°/100 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "5 hrs 20 min 20 sec corresponds to a longitude difference of:",
    "feedback": "80°05'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhich of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position 51°50.0'N 008°30.0'W?",
    "feedback": "Civil airport, VORDME, ILS, compulsory reporting point"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ground feature was observed on a relative bearing of 315° and 3 MIN later on a relative bearing of 270°.  The W/V is calm; aircraft GS 180 kt. What is the minimum distance between the aircraft and the ground feature?",
    "feedback": "9 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the time required to travel along the parallel of latitude 60° N between meridians 010° E and 030° W at a ground speed of 480 kt?",
    "feedback": "2 HR 30 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "What earth distance is represented by a line 47 mm long on a chart with a scale of 1:130 000?",
    "feedback": "3.3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following statements is correct concerning the appearance of great circles, with the exception of meridians, on a polar stereographic chart whose tangency is at the pole?",
    "feedback": "The higher the latitude the closer they approximate to a straight line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nYou are on radial 053 from POLE HILL 112.1 POL (N53°44.6' E002°06.2'W) and your DME indicates a distance of 55 NM.  What is the approximate position of your aircraft?",
    "feedback": "54°19'N 000°51'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies from waypoint 7 (63°00'N 073°00'W) to waypoint 8 (62°00'N 073°00'W). The aircraft position is (62°00'N 073°10'W). The cross track distance in relation to the planned track is:",
    "feedback": "4.7 NM R"
  },
  {
    "question": "Position A = (30°00.0'N 175°23.2'W) Position B = (30°00.0'N 173°48.1'E)  For the route from A to B the:",
    "feedback": "rhumb line distance is 561.8 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two locations A and B have the same latitude and are located on a meridian and anti-meridian. On a Lambert conical projection map, the angle between these two meridians is 156°. What is the parallel of the origin on this map?",
    "feedback": "60°N or S"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Magnetic heading = 255° VAR = 40°W GS = 375 kt W/V = 235°(T) / 120 kt Calculate the drift angle?",
    "feedback": "7° left"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nDetermine the initial track and distance from position A (N52º47', E005º05') to position B (N53º55', E005º52'):",
    "feedback": "Track 21º(M), 73 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nThe following bearing and distance information obtained from SPIJKERBOOR (SPY VORDME, N52º32' E004º51') is given:Radial 023ºDistance 63 NM\nFind the current position of the aircraft:",
    "feedback": "53º30'N, 005º33'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parallels of latitude are special cases of rhumb lines because of which property?",
    "feedback": "They intersect all meridians at the same angle of 90°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 140 kt,\nHDG (T) = 005°,\nW/V = 265/25kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "10R - 146 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Position A is located on the equator at longitude 130°00E. \nPosition B is located 100 NM from A on a bearing of 225°(T).\nThe coordinates of position B are:",
    "feedback": "01°11'S 128°49'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Latitude may be defined as",
    "feedback": "The angular distance measured along a meridian from the equator to a parallel of the latitude, measured in degrees, minutes, and seconds and named North or South"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you understand by the term \"white-out\"?",
    "feedback": "When the terrain is covered with snow and the horizon blends with the sky, visual determination of height becoming difficult"
  },
  {
    "question": "Route A - B is drawn on a Southern Polar Stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian. The True Track of the straight line at A is 120°. When passing the meridian of 100°E, the True Track is 090°. The Grid Track of this route on the chart is:",
    "feedback": "190°(G)"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 390 at a speed of Mach 0.821. OAT = ISA - 4°C. The compressibility factor is 0.942.\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "467 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the track error angle:\nPlanned track: 252°(T)Actual heading: 255°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 3° left",
    "feedback": "0°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Earth convergency between position A (65°30'N 100°25'W) and position B (65°30'N 125°25'W)?",
    "feedback": "22.75°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Define the term \"scale\".\nScale is:",
    "feedback": "The ratio between the length of a distance on the map and the length of the same distance on the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "A great circle track is drawn on a Lambert chart between positions X and Z in the Northern Hemisphere. The great circle true track at position X is measured as 300°, while at position Z, it is measured as 291°. If the constant of the cone of the chart is 0.809, what is the longitude difference between position X and Z?",
    "feedback": "011°07'"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying a low-level VFR route over a mountainous area, which is covered by snow, in high latitudes. Concerning power lines, they may be ....",
    "feedback": "dangerous, especially if they cross valleys, but poses less of a risk if they are situated along a ridge"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft following a standard instrument departure procedure, which requires a minimum climb gradient of 6%, climbs with a average TAS of 110 kt. A tailwind component of 15 kt is experienced. What is the minimum vertical speed (ft/min) to be flown to comply with the minimum climb gradient requirements?",
    "feedback": "750 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 190 kt,\nHDG (T) = 355°,\nW/V = 165/25kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "1L - 215 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the LMT and local date at \"A\" 102°30'E, when it is 10:45 LMT on 5th October at \"B\" 156°30'W?",
    "feedback": "04:01 LMT, 6th October"
  },
  {
    "question": "You want to fly 12000 ft above a frozen lake at elevation 930 ft AMSL. You have obtained \nQNH from an airfield in the area. Climbing, you observe that the air temperature at FL 80 is -20° C. What should your indicated altitude be when you are 12 000 ft above the frozen lake? Use the mechanical computer for the calculations",
    "feedback": "13950 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft is located on radial 045º and at a distance of 58 NM from VORDME Manchester, MCT (N53.4º, W002.3º). What are the corresponding coordinates of its position?(disregard corrections for slant range)",
    "feedback": "54º04'N, 001º10'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "The departure airfield is at 2000 ft elevation. Temperature at the field is +20°C, QNH 1013 hPa. The plan is to climb to FL 290, where outside air temperature is -40°C.\n\nThe average TAS in the climb should be calculated using what FL and temperature?",
    "feedback": "FL 200 with temperature -20°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR chart ED-4\nAn aircraft is flying a VFR flight from Strunkovice airport (LKSR, N49°05.0' E014°04.5') to Regensburg Oberhub airport (EDNR, N49°08.5' E012°04.9') vis Vilshofen airport (EDMV, N48°38.1' E013°11.7') and the mast of 1848 ft next to Mallersdorf.\nDue to inattention of the pilot, he/she drifted to the right and confused Elsenthal-Grafenau airport (EDNF, N48°49.4' E013°22.0') for Vilshofen airport, turning earlier right on the correct heading. When the pilot saw the mast with an elevation of 3750 ft, he/she started to doubt about his/her position. What is the best action to take?",
    "feedback": "Tune the VORDME RODING frequency to determine the position on the map"
  },
  {
    "question": "The duration of daylight changes at the highest rate around the (1) .... because the duration of daylight is (2) .... proportional to the rate of change of the Sun's declination",
    "feedback": "(1) equinoxes, (2) directly"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft takes off from the aerodrome of BRIOUDE (altitude 1 483 FT, QFE = 963 hPa, temperature = 32°C).\nFive minutes later, passing 5 000 FT on QFE, the second altimeter set on 1 013 hPa will indicate approximately :",
    "feedback": "6 400 FT"
  },
  {
    "question": "730 FT/MIN equals:",
    "feedback": "3.7 m/sec"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which formula is used to calculate the convergency between two positions relatively close to each other?\nConvergency = difference in longitude in.....",
    "feedback": "degrees x sin(mean latitude)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by the term 'polar circle'?",
    "feedback": "It is the parallel at the lowest latitude at which an observer can see the sun for 24 hours above the horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying under VFR by DR along a track of 312°(T), heading 310°(M) to account for the wind and the variation of 2°W.\nOn the first part of the leg, the pilot sees several gliders and turns to the left off the intended track to avoid them. After clearing the gliders the pilot spots a railway bridge and is able to fix the position of the aircraft. \nGiven the following information, what is the best magnetic heading to fly for the next check feature?\nFix position: 15 NM from the start of the leg and 2 NM off trackDistance to the next check feature: 18 NM",
    "feedback": "317°(M)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the approximate scale, expressed as ratio, of a low altitude en-route chart with a quoted scale of 1 inch = 15 NM?",
    "feedback": "1:1 094 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:  TAS = 155 kt, Track (T) = 305°, W/V = 160/18kt. Calculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "301 - 169 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The standard parallels are at 63°00'N and 37°00'N and the chart edges at 74°00'N and 24°00'N. At what approximate latitude will the actual scale on a Lambert chart be at a minimum?",
    "feedback": "50°00'N"
  },
  {
    "question": "G is in position 3500N 03445W. For a particular date sunrise at 3500N is in the Air Almanac listed as 0715. What is the time of sunrise at G, given in UTC?",
    "feedback": "0934 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of establishing a grid is",
    "feedback": "To provide a system for directions where a great circle has a constant direction, even if its true direction varies"
  },
  {
    "question": "A is at 5500N 15100W and B at 4500 N 16253W What is the departure?",
    "feedback": "458 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhat feature is shown on the chart at position 54º 40'N, 006º17'W?",
    "feedback": "Belfast (Aldergrove) aerodrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 30Surface wind from the tower: 02020KT\nWhat is the HWC?",
    "feedback": "4 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 122 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 985 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "8 HR 04 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying according to the flight log. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH, the aircraft is 3 NM south of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach the destination B from this position the TH should be:",
    "feedback": "292°"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying a VFR map-reading excercise, the pilot becomes lost because of isolated patches of fog hindering the ability to accurately pin-point the position. Which of the following should the pilot do in this situation?\n1) Maintain visual contact with the ground2) Communicate, if in contact with an Air Traffic Control (ATC) unit, to request assistance3) Fly a series of expanding circles to find a suitable check point4) Look at the terrain for hills and valley or line features such as a motorway, railway, river or coastline5) Read the map from map to ground",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 230 kt,\nHDG (T) = 250°,\nW/V = 205/10kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "2R - 223 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a topographical chart, contour lines that are very close together indicate that the terrain ....",
    "feedback": "is steep"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the Jeppesen GSPRM Training Route Manual - Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:Position A: N54°53', W005°18'Position B: N55°18', W003°35'\nFind the initial track for the flight from A to B and determine the distance from position A to the point of crossing meridian W004°00':",
    "feedback": "070°(M), 48 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the initial track direction of a straight line on a Polar Stereographic chart when flying from position A (50°N 130°E) to position B (50°N 130°W)?",
    "feedback": "040°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2:\nGiven the following bearing and range information obtained from TRENT TNT VOR/DME (53°03'N 001°40'W), what is the aircraft's position?\nRadial 093, Range 72 NM",
    "feedback": "52°59'N 000°20'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table.\nAt what UTC time does the sunset occur on the 03th October 2017 at Bodø airport in Norway (67°16'N 014°22'E)?",
    "feedback": "16:20 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the result when vector 1 is added to vector 2?",
    "feedback": "Vector D"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft descends from FL 250 to FL 100. The rate of descent is 1000 ft/min, the ground speed is 360 kt.  The flight path angle is:",
    "feedback": "1.6°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the result when vector 1 is added to vector 2?",
    "feedback": "Vector D"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nFind the average magnetic track and distance from Dublin VORDME (DUB, 53º30'N, 006º18'W) to Connaught VORDME (CON, 53º55'N, 008º49'W):",
    "feedback": "290º, 93 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the scale, expressed as a ratio, of a North Atlantic plotting chart which a quoted scale if 1 inch = 120 NM?",
    "feedback": "1:8 750 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the difference in LMT between Dublin (53°29'N, 006°15'W) and Bremen airport (53°09'N, 008°45'E):",
    "feedback": "01h 00m"
  },
  {
    "question": "Construct the triangle of velocities on a piece of paper, showing the following data:\n\nTH 305, TAS 135 Kt, W/V 230/40, Period of time from 1130 to 1145.\nWhat is the GS in this period of time?",
    "feedback": "130 Kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island is observed to be 15° to the left.\nThe aircraft heading is 120°(M), variation 17°(W).\nThe bearing °(T) from the aircraft to the island is:",
    "feedback": "088"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft departs from Schiphol (GMT + 1) airport and flies to Santa Cruz in Bolivia (South America) via Miami in Florida. The departure time (off blocks) is 07:45 ST at the 10th of November, taxi time before take off at Schiphol is 25 minutes. The flight time to Miami over the Atlantic Ocean is 09h20m. The total taxi time in Miami to and from the gate is 25 minutes. The time spent at the gate is 02h40m. From Miami to Santa Cruz the airborne time is 06h30m.\n\nCalculate the time and date of touch down in Santa Cruz in ST Bolivia if the difference between ST and UTC is 5 hours:",
    "feedback": "21:05 10th November"
  },
  {
    "question": "A circle is drawn on a polar stereographic chart. Select the best choice from the four options above:",
    "feedback": "Figure 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following statements is correct concerning the appearance of great circles, with the exception of meridians, on a Polar Stereographic chart whose tangency is at the pole ?",
    "feedback": "The higher the latitude the closer they approximate to a straight line"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft's rate of climb is calculated as 1100 feet per minute at a TAS of 200 kt. Determine the minimum headwind component required to achieve a climb gradient of 6% at that airspeed:",
    "feedback": "20 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the actual magnetic track of the aircraft:\nPlanned track: 350°(T)Heading: 004°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 12° leftVariation: 23°W",
    "feedback": "015°(M)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhich of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position 53º15'N 005º44'E?",
    "feedback": "Military airport, ILS, TACAN"
  },
  {
    "question": "A route is flown from (80°S 100°W) to (80°S 140°E). At 180°E/W the Grid Track (GT) and True Track (TT) on a Polar Stereographic chart, whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian, are respectively:",
    "feedback": "110°(G) and 290°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the tables below:  What is the duration of morning Civil Twilight at (66°48'N 095°26'W) on 27th of January?",
    "feedback": "01h 13 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SR/SS table for the 23rd of February at latitude 40°N gives:\nSR = 06:44\nSS = 17:44\n\nAt 12:00 Central European Time (UTC + 1) at 40°N:",
    "feedback": "the sun rises at 64°W"
  },
  {
    "question": "When proceeding, on a given date, along a parallel towards the east, the moment of sunrise will occur one hour earlier every 15° difference in longitude when it is expressed in:",
    "feedback": "UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rhumb-line distance between points A (60°00'N 002°30'E) and B (60°00'N 007°30'W) is:",
    "feedback": "300 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what would be the average ground speed during a descent from FL200 to an aerodrome at an elevation of 2000 ft?\nAverage descent speed: 200 kt CASAverage ISA deviation: -7°CAverage descent track: 165°(T)W/V at 2000 ft: 03030KTWV at 20000 ft: 09060KT",
    "feedback": "242 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table: When it is 1000 Standard Time in Kuwait, the Standard Time in Algeria is:",
    "feedback": "0800"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rhumb line track between position A (45°00'N, 010°00'W) and position B (48°30'N, 015°00'W) is approximately:",
    "feedback": "315"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transferring position lines",
    "feedback": "The lines of position are transferred along to the track line"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a Polar Stereographic Chart the grid lines:",
    "feedback": "run parallel to the reference meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a polar stereographic projection the chart convergency between two positions depends on the:",
    "feedback": "difference in longitude of the two positions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft is on radial 331º of Dublin VOR (DUB 53º30'N, 006º18'W) and radial 234º of Belfast VOR (BEL 54º39'N, 006º13'W). Find its position.",
    "feedback": "54º14'N, 007º07'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the value of the convergence factor on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "1.0"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator chart the distance between the meridians 2°E and 3°E is 60 mm. The scale of the chart at latitude 45°N is:",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 309 562"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nChart scale is 1 : 1 850 000. \nThe chart distance between two points is 4 centimetres. \nEarth distance is approximately :",
    "feedback": "40 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft follows a coastline during a particular time. This coast line is",
    "feedback": "A line of position"
  },
  {
    "question": "A chart has the scale 1 : 1 000 000. From A to B on the chart measures 1.5 inches (one inch equals 2.54 centimetres), the distance from A to B in NM is :",
    "feedback": "20.6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nThe following bearing and distance information obtained from SPIJKERBOOR (SPY VORDME, N52º32' E004º51') is given:Radial 334ºDistance 47 NM\nFind the current position of the aircraft:(note; slant range corrections should be ignored)",
    "feedback": "53°16'N, 004°17'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "On 4 February the Air Almanac lists 1941 as the time of sunset at 5000S.  An observer register sunset at 2113 UTC this day. What is the observers position?",
    "feedback": "5000S 02300W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 400\nOAT = - 65°C\nIAS = 260 kt\nInstrument and position error to be neglected\nCompressibility factor = 0.935\n\nCalculate the True Air Speed taking compressibility into account:",
    "feedback": "479 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Relief is usually portrayed by combinations of:\n1) Contour lines2) Shading3) Frequencies4) Colours5) Spot heights6) Graduated scale",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 4, 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nDistance 'A' to 'B' is 475 NM,\nPlanned GS 315 kt,\nATD 1000 UTC,\n1040 UTC - fix obtained 190 NM along track.\nWhat GS must be maintained from the fix in \norder to achieve planned ETA at 'B'?",
    "feedback": "340 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue HDG = 233°,\nTAS = 480 kt,\nTrack (T) = 240°,\nGS = 523 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "110/75kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The distance between two waypoints is 200 NM,\nTo calculate compass heading, the pilot used 2°E magnetic variation instead of 2°W.\nAssuming that the forecast W/V applied, what will the off track distance be at the second waypoint?",
    "feedback": "14 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft passes position A (60°00'N 120°00'W) on route to position B (60°00'N  140°30'W). \nWhat is the great circle track on departure from A?",
    "feedback": "279°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: fuel flow 8.4 t/HR, specific gravity 0.80, mach number 0.76, OAT –36°C.What is the specific fuel consumption ?",
    "feedback": "18.4 kg / NM air distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the average TAS to be used when performing a climb from a pressure altitude of 2000ft to FL200, given the following information:\nCAS = 150 ktOAT = ISA -15°C",
    "feedback": "181 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following scales are provided:\n1) 1:500 0002) 1 inch = 10 km3) 1/2 000 0004) 1 inch = 60 NM5) 1 cm = 10 NM\nthe two smallest scales are ....",
    "feedback": "3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Rhumb line is :",
    "feedback": "a line on the surface of the earth cutting all meridians at the same angle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the LMT at position 46°00'N 094°30'W when it is 14:00 UTC:",
    "feedback": "07:42 LMT"
  },
  {
    "question": "A flight leg of 90 NM is planned from A to B via an intermediate point C overhead a railway intersection. The planned heading is 037°(T) and the planned GS is 135 kt. After 12 minutes the pilot notices that the aircraft is 3 NM ahead and 3 NM left of the railway intersection, instead of 1 NM right, as expected. What is the required heading to reach B?",
    "feedback": "049°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 12Surface wind from the tower: 27015KT\nWhat is the TWC?",
    "feedback": "14 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a group of unlighted obstacles?",
    "feedback": "24"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 120 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 84 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "00 HR 42 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the diagrams most accurately represents the great circle route from A to B on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "Diagram 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sunrise in Dublin (53°29'N, 006°15'W) is 06:23 LMT. Calculate the sunrise at Bremen airport (53°29'N, 008°45'E) in LMT:",
    "feedback": "06:23"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nCAS = 190 kt\nPressure Altitude = 9000 ft\nOAT = ISA -15\n\nCalculate Mach number:",
    "feedback": "0.34"
  },
  {
    "question": "The standard parallels of a Lambert chart are 26°N and 48°N and the stated scale is 1 : 2 500 000.\n\nWhich statement is correct?",
    "feedback": "The scale at 28°N is smaller than the scale at 24°N"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the chart distance between longitudes 179°E and 175°W on a direct Mercator chart with a scale of 1 : 5 000 000 at the equator?",
    "feedback": "133 mm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 140 kt, FL 130, TAS 174. What is the OAT ?",
    "feedback": "0° C"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft obtains a relative bearing of 315° from an NDB at 0830. At 0840 the relative bearing from the same position is 270°. \nAssuming no drift and a GS of 240 kt, what is the approximate range from the NDB at 0840?",
    "feedback": "40 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:TALLA (TLA) VORDME (N55º30 W003º21')TURNBERRY (TRN) VORDME (N55º19' W004º47')Aircraft position: 54º58'N, 003º47'W\nFind the radials from TALLA and TURNBERRY to the aircraft positiion:",
    "feedback": "122º from TRN, 209º from TLA"
  },
  {
    "question": "The headquarter (HQ) of an airline is located at Schiphol, Netherlands (52°19'N 004°46'E, UTC +2 hours). One of its aircraft departs from Quito, Ecuador (00°08'S 078°21'W, UTC -5 hours) at 22:30 ST on the 26th August local date and flies to Nairobi, Kenya (01°19'S 036°56'E, UTC +3 hours). The flight time is 11 hours 14 minutes. What is the Standard Time (ST) and local date at the airline HQ when the aircraft arrives at its destination?",
    "feedback": "16:44 ST on the 27th August"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information for a flight from location B (84°S 119°E) to location A (84°S), presented on a Polar Stereographic chart as a straight line, calculate the longitude of location A.\nInitial track at B: 237°(T)Final track at A: 303°(T)",
    "feedback": "053°E"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aerodrome is located at Mean Sea Level and its traffic pattern altitude is at 2000 ft. Given the following information, to reach downwind at the traffic pattern altitude, a 3° path descent must be initiated at (1) .... prior to downwind, and it will last for (2) ....\nCruise altitude: 5500 ftAverage rate of descent for a 3° path: 750 ft/min",
    "feedback": "(1) 12 NM; (2) 4 minutes 40 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "Some states implement daylight saving time (sometimes referred to as summer time) by advancing the clocks 1 hour in spring. Which of the following options is an effect of this?",
    "feedback": "The daylight is shifted towards later in the day"
  },
  {
    "question": "Position \"Elephant Point\" is situated at (58°00'N 135°30'W). Standard Time for this location is listed in the Air Almanac as UTC -8. \n\nIf sunset occurs at 00:57 UTC on 21 January, what is the time of sunset in LMT?",
    "feedback": "15:55 on January 20th"
  },
  {
    "question": "As seen from an observer on the surface of the earth",
    "feedback": "The apparent sun is always in the plane of the ecliptic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the average TAS for a climb from FL050 to FL170. The climb is performed with a constant CAS of 150 kt. OAT: ISA -20°C.",
    "feedback": "176 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two positions at the same latîtude are marked on an aeronautical chart and the meridians at those positions converge with an angle of 30°. The effect of this convergence is that the true track of...",
    "feedback": "a straight line drawn between those two positions will change by 30°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the ETA at waypoint 3 (Z) if the following values are given:\nWPT 1 (X): ATA 13:04 UTCWPT 2 (Y): ETA 13:43 UTCWPT 2 (Y): ATA 13:51 UTCWPT 3 (Z): ETA?",
    "feedback": "14:22 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete line 5 of the 'FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG', positions 'J' to 'K'.\nWhat is the HDG°(M) and ETA?",
    "feedback": "HDG 337°  -  ETA 1422 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Isogrives are lines that connect positions that have:",
    "feedback": "the same grivation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue course A to B = 250°\nDistance A to B = 315 NM\nTAS = 450 kt. \nW/V = 200°/60kt.\nETD A = 0650 UTC.\nWhat is the ETA at B?",
    "feedback": "0736 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft departs point A at 12:15 on a planned route of 80 NM with an initial heading of 235°. At 12:27, after travelling 40 NM, a railroad track is passed, crossing the route at 90°. At 12:33 the aircraft is 4 NM to the left of the intended track. What heading must be flown to reach the intended destination and what will be the ETA?",
    "feedback": "251°, 12:39"
  },
  {
    "question": "A ground feature appears 30° to the left of the centre line of the CRT of an airborne weather radar. If the heading of the aircraft is 355° (M) and the magnetic variation is 15° East, the true bearing of the aircraft from the feature is:",
    "feedback": "160°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the danger about power lines, when flying VFR over a snowy area?",
    "feedback": "The represent a danger when power lines cross the valley"
  },
  {
    "question": "On navigational charts, the magnetic variation is indicated with isogonals. Stage the reason why the year, for which the isogonals are valid, is noted in the chart index.",
    "feedback": "The magnetic variation changes over time due to the movement of the magnetic pole inside the Earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nYou are approaching POLE HILL VOR (POL) on radial 233. The DME indicates a distance of 40 NM. What is your approximate aircraft position?",
    "feedback": "53º19'N, 002º58'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 135 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 433 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "3 HR 12 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "If you are flying along a parallel of latitude, you are flying:",
    "feedback": "a rhumb line track"
  },
  {
    "question": "What scenario will give the greatest difference between nautical air miles and ground miles?",
    "feedback": "Headwind at high altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft leaves departure aerodrome A (N33°56' W118°24')), UTC -7 hours, at 21:15 Standard Time on the 17th February. After a flight of 15 hours 25 minutes, what is the Standard Time (ST) and local date of arrival at aerodrome B (N22°18' E113°55'), UTC +8 hours?",
    "feedback": "03:40 ST, 19th February"
  },
  {
    "question": "Crossing the North Atlantic on a westbound track from position X (62°N, 020°W) to position Y (63°N, 030°W), the average true track is 282.2°. On a Lambert chart with standard parallels at 75°N and 30°N, the direction of the straight line is approximately....",
    "feedback": "286° at position X"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR chart ED-4\nFlying VFR from Griesau (N48°57' E12°25') to Arnbruck (N49°7' E12°59'). What is the highest obstacle or elevation, whichever is higher, considering a 5 NM radius around the aerodromes?",
    "feedback": "4055 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Compare two points at the same latitude and longitude, point A being at Mean Sea Level and point B at 10000 ft altitude. \nAt point B, sunrise will occur....",
    "feedback": "earlier, due to the increased visual horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator chart at latitude 30°N, a distance of 8.3 cm on the chart equals to 40 NM on ground. What is the same distance on ground at a latitude of 45°N?",
    "feedback": "60 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 465 kt,\nHDG (T) = 124°,\nW/V = 170/80kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "8L - 415 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying from A (50°S 040°W) to B (60°S 050°W). The initial great circle track is 206°. What will be the rhumb line track when passing 045°W?",
    "feedback": "210°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates an uncontrolled route?",
    "feedback": "16"
  },
  {
    "question": "While flying on an easterly track and crossing the dateline, the Local Time (LT) will (1) .... and the date (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) stay unchanged, (2) goes back by one day"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Mercator projection the distance between (17°N 035°E) and (17°N 040°E) is 5 cm. The scale at 57°N is approximately;",
    "feedback": "1: 6 052 030"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR Chart ED-4\nA light aircraft takes off from Straubing aerodrome EDMS (48°54'N 012°31'E) and arrives at Roding city (49°12'N 012°31'E) after 6 minutes of flight. What is the aircraft's ground speed?",
    "feedback": "180 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following formula is correct for the calculation of Maximum Range ?",
    "feedback": "Maximum Range = Safe Fuel available x Specific Range"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following:\nTrue track: 192°\nMagnetic variation: 7°E\nDrift angle: 5° left\nWhat is the magnetic heading required to maintain the given track?",
    "feedback": "190°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two positions at the same latitude are marked on a Polar Stereographic chart and the meridians at those positions converge with an angle of 30°. The effect of this convergence is that the true track of ......",
    "feedback": "a straight line drawn between those two positions will change by 30°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 125 kt,\nTrue HDG = 355°,\nW/V = 320°(T)/30kt.\nCalculate the true track and GS?",
    "feedback": "005 - 102 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the vertex of a great circle is always true?",
    "feedback": "In the vertex the True Track is 090° or 270°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 200 kt,\nTrack (T) = 073°,\nW/V = 210/20kt.\nCalculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "077 - 214 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the wind from FRUGES to WIMEREUX assuming that the ground speed is 115 kt. Use the date provided in the table above.",
    "feedback": "200°(T)/20 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nIAS 120 kt,\nFL 80,\nOAT +20°C. \nWhat is the TAS?",
    "feedback": "141 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the True Heading (TH) and TAS:\nTrue Track: 321°GS: 123 ktW/V 213°(T)/21 kt",
    "feedback": "TH 311°, TAS 118 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 10:15 the reading from a VOR/DME station is 211°/90 NM, at 10:20 the reading from the same VOR/DME station is 211°/120 NM.\n\nCompass Heading = 200°\nVariation in the area = 31°W\nDeviation = +1°\nTAS = 390 kt\n\nThe wind vector (T) is approximately:",
    "feedback": "110°/70 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the rate of descent (ROC) from FL180 to pressure altitude 4500 ft:\nAverage TAS: 125 ktAverage HWC: 30 ktGround distance during the descent: 20 NM",
    "feedback": "1050 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is in the position 86°N 020°E. When following a rhumb line track of 085°(T) it will:",
    "feedback": "fly via a spiral to the north pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the Wind Correction Angle (WCA) and the ground speed using the following data:\nTrue course: 353°TAS: 160 ktW/V 260/35\nWCA and GS are:",
    "feedback": "WCA 13°L, GS 158 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what is the approximate position of B?\nPosition A: 31°00'S, 176°17'WRumb line track from A to B: 270°(T)Initial great circle track from A to B: 266.2°(T)",
    "feedback": "31°00'S, 168°58'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete line 3 of the 'FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG', positions 'E' to 'F'.\nWhat is the HDG°(M) and ETA?",
    "feedback": "HDG 105°  -  ETA 1205 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the Standard Time (ST) and date of arrival in Chile, given the following information:\nRoute: New Zealand to Chile, crossing the International Date Line on an easterly courseDeparture time and date: 03:00 UTC, 19th NovemberFlight time: 12 hours 30 minutesNew Zealand ST: UTC +12 hoursChile ST: UTC -4 hours",
    "feedback": "11:30, 19th November"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying from point A (25°35'N 178°25'E) to point B (32°45'N 165°26'W). What is the angle between the great circle and the rhumb line at point A?",
    "feedback": "3.94°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The distance from A to B is 120 NM. After flying half way on the route, the aircraft is 3 NM to the left of course. In order to fly  directly to point B, the heading alteration is:",
    "feedback": "6°R"
  },
  {
    "question": "The irregular orbital speed of the Earth as described in the Kepler’s Second Law...",
    "feedback": "causes the different length of apparent solar days"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft departs position A on the 170°00'E meridian at 01:30 Local Mean Time (LMT) on 11 February on an easterly course. It arrives at position B on the 160°00'W meridian 3:00 hours later.\nWhat is the LMT and local date of arrival at position B?",
    "feedback": "06:30, 10th February"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"sidereal\" is used",
    "feedback": "To describe a situation or relationship concerning the stars"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1023 hPa. The TAS is 100 kts, the headwind component is 20 kts and the rate of climb is 1000 ft/min. Top of climb is FL100. At what distance from the airport will this be achieved?",
    "feedback": "11.1 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The position of the aircraft is N55°00' W070°00'. The variation at the aircraft's position is 21°W. A VOR is situated at position N50°00' W065°00'. The variation at the VOR is 19°, initial magnetic track of the great circle from the aircraft position to the VOR is 168°.\nWhich radial is the aircraft on?",
    "feedback": "350"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 150. The QNH, given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 1500 ft is 1010 hPa. OAT = -25°C. The elevation of the highest obstacle along the route is 7000 ft. Use 1hPa = 30 ft.\n\nCalculate the aircraft's clearance above the highest obstacle on this route (rounded off in hundreds of feet):",
    "feedback": "7400 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the figure.\nAccording to ICAO Annex 4, which of the following is the VOR check point?",
    "feedback": "II"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft tracks radial 200 inbound to a VOR station with a Magnetic Heading (MH) of 010°. After being overhead the VOR station the aircraft tracks radial 090 outbound with a MH of 080°. The TAS is 240 kt and the magnetic variation in the area is 5°W.\n\nWhat is the wind vector (T)?",
    "feedback": "320°/50 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is working with a VFR chart whose scale is 1:500 000. How long (in cm) would a straight line drawn on the chart betwen two positions that are 36 NM apart on the ground measure?",
    "feedback": "13 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 250 kt,\nHDG (T) = 029°,\nW/V = 035/45kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "1L - 205 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nMagnetic heading 311°\nDrift angle 10° left\nRelative bearing of NDB 270°\nWhat is the magnetic bearing of the NDB measured from the aircraft?",
    "feedback": "221°"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart with standard parallels at 54°N and 59°N is used for navigation.\nThe straight line between A (55°00'.0N, 165°00'.0E) and B (58°00'.0N, 154°00'.0E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle along the straight line in A is 301°.\n\nCalculate the direction (°T) of the straight line in position B.",
    "feedback": "292°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is departing from an airport which has an elevation of 2000 ft and the QNH is 1003 hPa. The TAS is 100 kts, the headwind component is 20 kts and the rate of climb is 500 ft/min. Top of climb is FL050. At what distance from the airport will this be achieved?",
    "feedback": "7.2 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The reported surface wind from the Control Tower is 240°/35 kt. Runway 30 (300°). \nWhat is the cross-wind component?",
    "feedback": "30 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal chart the distance between two parallels of latitude having a \ndifference of latitude = 2° , is measured to be 112 millimetres. The distance between two meridians, spaced 2°  longitude, is, according to the chart 70 NM. The parallel of origin (selected parallel) runs through the middle of the described square. What is the convergence for a  dlong of 15°  on this map?",
    "feedback": "12,18°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nA North polar stereographic chart whose grid is aligned with the zero meridian. \nGrid track 344°, \nLongitude 115°00'W,\nCalculate the true course?",
    "feedback": "229°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Summer and winter solstice are the points of time when the sun reaches:",
    "feedback": "its highest/lowest declination"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kepler's second law states that:",
    "feedback": "the radius vector sun-earth sweeps out equal areas in equal time."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average TAS climbing from 1500 ft up to FL 180,  given a temperature ISA +15°C, a CAS 230 KT and QNH 1032 ?",
    "feedback": "283kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a mechanical computer, determine the TAS, given the following information:\nAltitude: 1500 ftOAT: -15°CIAS/CAS: 120 kt",
    "feedback": "117 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are climbing to FL280 in ISA conditions, maintaining a constant CAS of 250 kt. At the beginning of the climb your instrument cross-check shows TAS at 336 kt and Mach 0.55. The instruments are checked again at some point during the climb. Which options contains reading that you would expect to see?",
    "feedback": "TAS 357 kt and Mach 0.59"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nDistance 'A' to 'B' is 90 NM,\nFix obtained 60 NM along and 4 NM to the right of course.\nWhat heading alteration must be made to reach 'B'?",
    "feedback": "12° Left"
  },
  {
    "question": "A planned route has a true course of 179°.\nThe true heading is 185°.\nAfter 23 minutes en-route a fix is overflown that is 44 NM away from the departure point and 6 NM right of the course line.\nThe average drift angle for this flight is:",
    "feedback": "2° to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying according to the flight log. After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH, the aircraft is 3 NM north of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach the destination B from this position the TH should be:",
    "feedback": "258°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the change in CAS required to reduce the TAS of an aircraft from 150 kt to 105 kt, given the following information and using a mechanical computer:\nCruising Level: FL070OAT: +25°C",
    "feedback": "39 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An arc of 1 minute of a meridian equals",
    "feedback": "1 nautical mile"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using both the Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) and the clock code technique, calculate the crosswind component to the nearest full know for the following information given:\nRunway 13Surface wind (from ATC): 12030KTVariation: 10°W",
    "feedback": "5 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following:\nMagnetic heading: 060°\nMagnetic variation: 8°W\nDrift angle: 4° right\nWhat is the true track?",
    "feedback": "056°"
  },
  {
    "question": "refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhich of the following lists all the aeronautical chart symbols shown at position 54º56.5'N, 002º48.0'W?",
    "feedback": "Civil airport, NDB/DME"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is using conventional navigation to fly on a non-RNAV airway, defined by the fixes ASMIK-SEVAN-PEMAN, with a published course of 104°(T). To fly the centre line of the airway he/she maintains a heading of 099°(T). After having overflown waypoint SEVAN and having travelled for 20 NM, the pilot plots the position to be 3 NM off-course towards the North.\nCalculate the average drift after overflying waypoint SEVAN.",
    "feedback": "4° left"
  },
  {
    "question": "An island appears 60° to the left of the centre line on an airborne weather radar display. What is the true bearing of the aircraft from the island if at the time of observation the aircraft was on a magnetic heading (MH) of 276° with the magnetic variation (VAR) 10°E?",
    "feedback": "046°"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what approximate date is the earth closest to the sun (perihelion)?",
    "feedback": "Beginning of January"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information and using a mechanical computer, calculate the equivalent wind component.\nTrack: 240°(T)Wind vector: 030°(T)/25 ktTAS: 90 kt",
    "feedback": "Tailwind 22 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft overflies waypoint 1 at 10:34 UTC and is overhead waypoint 2 at 10:49 UTC. The measured distance on the chart between the two waypoints is 13.8 cm. If 1 cm on the chart represents 3.1 NM on the Earth, what groundspeed has been flown between the two waypoints?",
    "feedback": "171 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete line 1 of the 'FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG'; positions 'A' to 'B'.\nWhat is the HDG°(M) and ETA?",
    "feedback": "268°  -  1114 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the True Track (TT) and TAS:\nTrue Heading: 340°Groundspeed: 128 ktW/V: 308°(T) / 32 kt",
    "feedback": "TT = 348°, TAS = 154 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is flying a VFR cross-country flight and spots a landmark at a bearing of 45° relative to the track. After 3 minutes the bearing to the landmark is 90° relative to the track. If the TAS is 90 kt and there is a tailwind of 30 kt, what is the distance to the landmark at the time of the second bearing?",
    "feedback": "6 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements most accurately describes a great circle route on a Lambert conformal conic chart? A straight line will approximate to a great circle course if the...",
    "feedback": "straight line is close to the parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "The distance measured between two points on a navigation map is 42 mm (millimetres). The scale of the chart is 1:1 600 000.\nThe actual distance between these two point is approximately:",
    "feedback": "36.30 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the W/V by using the multi-drift method (multiple drift W/V) when the following observations have been made while TAS was 187 Kt:  MH 015: Drift 7R, MH 075: Drift 8R, MH 177: Drift 3L",
    "feedback": "W/V 328M/29"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert chart (standard parallels 37°N and 65°N), with respect to the straight line drawn on the map the between A ( N49° W030°) and B (N48° W040°), the:",
    "feedback": "great circle and rhumb line are to the south"
  },
  {
    "question": "Grivation is 56W when",
    "feedback": "GH is 103°  and MH is 159°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Daylight Saving Time (Summer Time)",
    "feedback": "All 3 answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what heading correction is required to proceed directly to position B?\nPlanned track from A to B: 284°(T)Planned distance between A and B: 50 NMPlanned ground speed: 132 ktTime between A and fix position: 10 minutesAt fix position: 4 NM right off course and 2 NM behind DR position",
    "feedback": "20° to the left"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between UTC and GMT?",
    "feedback": "UTC is slightly more accurate than GMT, but the difference between the two is so\nsmall that it has no importance in everyday navigation of aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "When a chart meets the ICAO recommendations for conformity, what does this mean when using this chart for navigational purposes?",
    "feedback": "A straight line drawn on the chart will approximate a great circle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a Flight Information Region (FIR) boundary?",
    "feedback": "13"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a direct Mercator projection, at latitude 45° North, a certain length represents 70 NM. \nAt latitude 30° North, the same length represents approximately:",
    "feedback": "86 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "During the summer months, some states apply daylight savings. What does this mean?",
    "feedback": "In the afternoon/evening, an hour of daylight is gained"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following alternatives is correct when you cross the international date line?",
    "feedback": "The date will increase if you are crossing on a westerly heading"
  },
  {
    "question": "The duration of civil twilight is the time:",
    "feedback": "between sunset and when the centre of the sun is 6° below the true horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of aeronautical chart symbol No. 12?",
    "feedback": "Aeronautical ground light"
  },
  {
    "question": "The convergency on a direct Mercator chart is:",
    "feedback": "0°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The polar circles are situated at:",
    "feedback": "66.5°N and S"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"True North\" is",
    "feedback": "The direction along any meridian toward the true north pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft leaves London (UK) for Vancouver (British Columbia, Canada) on the 5th of July at 10:00 UTC. The flight time is 11 hours. Assume that the Daylight Saving Time (DST) applies in both places. What will be the Standard Time and date of arrival at Vancouver?",
    "feedback": "14:00 ST, 5th July"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the initial track direction of a straight line on a Polar Stereographic chart when flying from position A (83°N 130°E) to position B (83°N 160°W)?",
    "feedback": "055°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately how many nautical miles correspond to 12 cm on a map with a scale of 1 : 2 000 000?",
    "feedback": "130"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 27th of February, at 52°S and 040°E, the sunrise is at 0243 UTC. \nOn the same day, at 52°S and 035°W, the sunrise is at:",
    "feedback": "0743 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 105 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 103 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "00 HR 59 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assuming mid-latitudes (40° to 50°N/S).\nAt which time of year is the relationship between the length of day and night, as well as the rate of change of declination of the sun, changing at the greatest rate?",
    "feedback": "Spring equinox and autumn equinox"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 225 kt,\nHDG (°T) = 123°,\nW/V = 090/60kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "134 - 178 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS 487kt, \nFL 330, \nTemperature ISA + 15. \n\nCalculate the Mach Number:",
    "feedback": "0.81"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal chart the scale is correct",
    "feedback": "At the standard parallels"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long will it take to fly 5 NM at a ground speed of 269 Kt ?",
    "feedback": "1 MIN 07 SEC"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the definition of \"Morning Civil Twilight\"?",
    "feedback": "Morning civil twilight is the period in the morning from the centre of the sun is 6°\nbelow the horizon until the upper limb of the sun appears at the horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transferring position lines can be done with",
    "feedback": "Radials, DME, QDM/QDR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the tables. Carrasco International Airport is located in the Standard Time (ST) zone of Uruguay. What is the Standard Time (S) of sunset at Carrasco International Airport (34°50'S 056°02'W) on October 17, 2017?",
    "feedback": "19:00"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot receives the following signals from a VOR DME station: \nradial 180°+/- 1°, distance = 200 NM. \nWhat is the approximate error?",
    "feedback": "+/- 3.5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 95 kt,\nHDG (T) = 075°,\nW/V = 310/20kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "9R - 108 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Geodetic latitude and geocentric latitude coincide:",
    "feedback": "at the poles and on the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 130 kt,\nTrack (T) = 003°,\nW/V = 190/40kt.\nCalculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "001 - 170 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sidereal day is:",
    "feedback": "of constant duration"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 20Surface wind from the tower: 14030KT\nWhat is the HWC?",
    "feedback": "15 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Fuel flow 42 US Gal / HR, specific gravity 0.72, TAS 210 KT.What is the specific fuel consumption ?",
    "feedback": "0.545 kg / NM air distance"
  },
  {
    "question": "You should follow a track due north taking account of a north westerly wind. You calculated a WCA –8°.",
    "feedback": "A track error of 2° (right) shows a drift of 10° right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: A (50°N 070°W) and B (50°N 080°W), and the position of one of the vertices of the great circle between A and B as being equal to (50°06.4'N 075°00.0'W), what is the position of the other vertex of this great circle?",
    "feedback": "(50°06.4S, 105°00.0'E)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which figure in the diagram represents the geocentric latitude of position P, which is situated above the surface of the ellipsoid?",
    "feedback": "Figure B"
  },
  {
    "question": "A map is conformal when",
    "feedback": "The meridians and the parallels of latitude intersect at right angles and when the scale from any selected point is the same in all directions"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying from A (60°N 060°W) to B (60°N 070°W). The true great circle track, when passing 064°W will be ....",
    "feedback": "270.8°"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct definition of geodetic longitude?",
    "feedback": "The angle between the plane of the meridian that passes through a point on the surface of the ellipsoid and the plane of the prime meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "for this question use GSPRM chart E(LO)2\nFind the true track and distance from BELFAST VORDME (BEL 54°39'N 006°13'W) to DEAN CROSS DME (DCS 54°43'N 003°20'W):",
    "feedback": "087°(T) and 100 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 130 kt, PA 1000 ft, TAS 127 What is the OAT ?",
    "feedback": "-8° C"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies over a small lake which is located some degrees to the left of the planned track. Given the following information, what is the drift angle (rounded the the nearest full degree), using the 1 in 60 rule?\nTAS: 100 ktTailwind component: 15 ktFlight time from previous waypoint: 11 minOff-track distance between the lake and the track: 2.4 NM",
    "feedback": "7°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeronautical chart is conformal when:",
    "feedback": "at any point the scale over a short distance in the direction of the parallel is equal to the scale in the direction of the meridian and the meridians are perpendicular to the parallels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nCAS = 190 kt\nPressure Altitude = 9000 ft\nOAT = ISA -15\n\nCalculate TAS:",
    "feedback": "211 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Standard Time and date in Ecuador (UTC -5 hours) if it is 03:25 UTC on the 21 of January?",
    "feedback": "22:25, 20th January"
  },
  {
    "question": "At mid and high latitudes, what is the main cause of the duration of daylight changing throughout the year?",
    "feedback": "The inclination of the Earth's spin axis in relation to the plane of rotation around the Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "The True Course in the flight log is 270°, the forecast wind is 045°(T)/15 kt and the TAS is 120 kt.\n\nAfter 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH the aircraft is 3 NM south of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position.\n\nThe track angle error (TAE) is:",
    "feedback": "5°L"
  },
  {
    "question": "for this question use Jeppesen GSPRM chart AT(HI)5:\nA pilot wants to check the position of the aircraft with raw data. For this, NDB \"RB\" (N74 44.8 W094 59.7) is tuned at the ADF. Calculate the direction of the position line from the NDB for plotting on the Polar Stereographic Chart.\nRMI reading: 295°(M)DR: N75°10 W089°58'Deviation is negligible",
    "feedback": "070°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the true heading and the ground speed using the following data:\nTrue course: 188°TAS: 420 ktW/V 260/90\nTrue heading and GS are:",
    "feedback": "True heading 200°, GS 383 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the actual magnetic track of the aircraft:\nPlanned track: 283°(T)Heading: 289°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 7° rightVariation: 12°W",
    "feedback": "308°(M)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The sun moves from East to West at a speed of 15° longitude an hour. What ground speed will give you the opportunity to observe the sun due south at all times at 6000N?",
    "feedback": "450 Kt."
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line from A (75°S 120°E) to B (75°S 160°E) is drawn on a Polar Stereographic chart. When passing the meridian 155°E, the true track is:",
    "feedback": "075°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue HDG = 133°,\nTAS = 225 kt,\nTrack (T) = 144°,\nGS = 206 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "075/45kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the table.\nHobart International Airport is located in the Standard Time (ST) zone of Tasmania, which is UTC +10 hours. What is the Standard Time (ST) of sunset at Hobart International Airport, Australia (42°50'S 147°31'E) on the 11th October 2017?",
    "feedback": "18:29 ST"
  },
  {
    "question": "The rhumb line track from A (53°50'N, 006°55'E) to B (53°00'N, 015°40'E) is 099°.\n\nCalculate the final True Track along the great circle:",
    "feedback": "103°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the ground speed (GS) of an aircraft travelling from WINDFARM to WIMEREUX, given that it arrives at WIMEREUX at 14:43.",
    "feedback": "115 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft following a standard instrument departure procedure, which requires a minimum climb gradient of 6.6%, climbs with a average ground speed of 180 kt. What is the minimum vertical speed (ft/min) to be flown to comply with the minimum climb gradient requirements?",
    "feedback": "1188 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on meridians:",
    "feedback": "All meridians run in true direction from South to North"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 230 kt, FL 120, OAT -10°C. What is the TAS?",
    "feedback": "273 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the LMT at 4500N 07345E when the time is 1246 UTC?",
    "feedback": "1741 LMT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parallels of latitude, except the equator, are:",
    "feedback": "Rhumb lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "An observer is situated on the parallel of latitude of 23.5°S. Which statement about the passage of the apparent sun in relation to this position is correct?",
    "feedback": "It passes through the zenith once a year around December 22nd."
  },
  {
    "question": "The exact equation for calculating the convergency between two meridians running through two different positions is",
    "feedback": "Convergency=GCTTin-GCTTfin"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is tracking the 105° Radial inbound to a VOR in the Northern Hemisphere. The magnetic variation is 4°E at the aircraft's position and 8°E at the VOR. The earth convergency between the aircraft's position and the VOR is 6°.\nWhat is the true course from the VOR that should be plotted to achieve a straight line from the VOR to the aircraft on a Direct Mercator chart?",
    "feedback": "116°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The accuracy of the manually calculated DR position of an aircraft is, among other things, affected by:",
    "feedback": "the flight time since the last position update"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the chart characteristic which achieves the ICAO requirement of a straight line on an en-route chart approximating to a great circle track on the Earth?",
    "feedback": "Chart convergence approximates to Earth convergence"
  },
  {
    "question": "The diameter of the Earth is approximately:",
    "feedback": "12 700 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is correct about the apparent solar day?",
    "feedback": "The apparent solar day is the period between two successive transits of the true sun through the same meridian."
  },
  {
    "question": "By 'Ecliptic' is meant:",
    "feedback": "the apparent yearly path of the sun around the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the convergency factor on a Direct Mercator projection?",
    "feedback": "0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on longitude",
    "feedback": "The largest value of longitude is 180º"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many NM would an aircraft travel in 1 HR 10 MIN if the GS were 147 kt?",
    "feedback": "171.5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "During a low level flight 2 parallel roads that are crossed at right angles by an aircraft. The time between these roads can be used to check the aircraft:",
    "feedback": "ground speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Location A is at 50°N 030°W and location B is at 50°S 030°W. On 27th November it is noted that:",
    "feedback": "Sunrise will be later at A than at B and sunset will be earlier at A than at B"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time difference is 9 hours 17 minutes. Calculate the corresponding difference in longitude:",
    "feedback": "139°15'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The direction of the Earth's rotation on its axis is such that",
    "feedback": "Observed from the point above the North Pole, the rotation is counterclockwise."
  },
  {
    "question": "The time interval between sunrise and sunset is dependent on:",
    "feedback": "the declination of the sun and the latitude of the observer."
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a VOR/DME?",
    "feedback": "3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given an intended track 270°, W/V 040/40, TAS 180 MPH",
    "feedback": "The DR position is on the intended track"
  },
  {
    "question": "The circumference of the parallel of latitude at 60°N is approximately:",
    "feedback": "10 800 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the extract from a flight plan on the table below.\n\nCalculate the average TAS between AA and EE:",
    "feedback": "252.9 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Local Mean Time at position 65°15'N 161°15'W, at 19:00 UTC?",
    "feedback": "08:15"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete line 4 of the 'FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG', positions 'G' to 'H'.\nWhat is the HDG°(M) and ETA?",
    "feedback": "HDG 344°  -  ETA 1336 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference in longitude between A (11°28'N 045°34'E) and B (44°36'S 009°18'W)?",
    "feedback": "54°52'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the approximate Wind Correction Angle (WCA).\nCrosswind component: 20 kt from right to leftTrack: 340°(T)TAS: 90 kt",
    "feedback": "+13°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft leaves departure aerodrome A (S33°57' E151°11'), UTC + 10 hours, at 09:30 Standard Time on the 15th July. After a flight of 9 hours 40 minutes, what is the Standard Time (ST) and local date of arrival at aerodrome B (N21°25' W157°55'), UTC - 10 hours?",
    "feedback": "23:10 ST, 14th July"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is descending from FL280 at a constant Mach number of 0.70 in ISA conditions. At the beginning of the descent, the pilot, after checking the instruments, reads a CAS of 274 kt and a TAS of 416 kt. At some point during the descent, when the instruments are re-checked, which value of TAS and CAS would the pilot expect to read?",
    "feedback": "CAS: 324 kt, TAS: 430 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue HDG = 145°,\nTAS = 240 kt,\nTrack (T) = 150°,\nGS = 210 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "115/35kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven the following information, what is the aircraft's position, if both DME ranges are decreasing?\nST ABBS (SAB) VORDME (55°54'N 002°12'W), range 81 NMTURNBERRY (TRN) VORDME (55°19'N 004°47'W), range 38 NMAircraft's track: 155°(T)(slant range correction should be ignored)",
    "feedback": "55°57'N 004°37'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is descending from FL 270 to FL 100 following MT 054° and maintaining CAS 250 KT.Given are variation 13°E, temperatures ISA-10°C, W/V 020/60What is your GS?",
    "feedback": "281 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "At what approximate latitude is the length of one minute of arc along a meridian equal to one NM (1852 m) correct?",
    "feedback": "45°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft in flight is required to find its position with two DME readings. Connaught DME (CON, 53º55'N, 008º49'W) reads 29 NM, Sligo DME (SLG, 54º17'N, 008º36'W) reads 26 NM. The aircraft is on a heading of 090º with both readings increasing. Find its position.",
    "feedback": "54º00'N, 008º00'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the convergence of the meridians on a chart. What is the trigonometric function related to the parallel of origin used to determine the constant of the cone?",
    "feedback": "Sine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what is the rate of descent /ROD) for the final approach segment of the destination airport?\nGP angle: 5.5°TAS: 130 ktHWC: 20 ktAltitude: 2000 ft",
    "feedback": "1000 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 510 kt.\nDistance A to B = 43 NM\nWhat is the time (MIN) from A to B?",
    "feedback": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two places on the parallel of 47°S lie 757.8 km apart. Calculate the difference in longitude:",
    "feedback": "10°00'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel flow per HR is 22 US-GAL, total fuel on board is 83 IMP GAL.\nWhat is the endurance?",
    "feedback": "4 HR 32 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a compulsory reporting point?",
    "feedback": "10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Position A is (31°00'S 176°17'W)\nRhumb line track (T) from A to B is 270°\nInitial great circle track (T) from A to B is 266.2°\n\nThe approximate position of B is:",
    "feedback": "(31°00'S 168°58'E)"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many NM would an aircraft travel in 2 HR 7 MIN if the GS were 270 kt?",
    "feedback": "571.5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:DEAN CROSS (DCS) 115.2 MHz, 54°43'N 003°20'WNATEB, 55°02'N, 001°42'W\nCalculate the true track and distance from DCS to NATEB:",
    "feedback": "071°, 60 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is flying VFR in VMC at 1500 ft above ground, passing small separated villages. The pilot chooses a church tower in a village as a turning point to a new course. After completing the turn and flying towards the next waypoint, which is show on the chart as a framework tower, the pilot is not able to find the tower at the expected time overhead. What is a likely reason for the navigation error?",
    "feedback": "The pilot changed course at a wrong village"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal projection the scale at a point at 60°N in the direction of True North is 1:1.000.000.\n\nWhat is the scale at the same point in an easterly direction?",
    "feedback": "1:1.000.000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Begin of morning civil twilight and end of evening civil twilight are defined by :",
    "feedback": "sun altitude is 6° below the celestial horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements:",
    "feedback": "The exact length of a 1' of arc varies a little from position to position because the Earth radius vary"
  },
  {
    "question": "A semi great circle on the Earth running from the North Pole to the South Pole is called:",
    "feedback": "meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart AT(HI)5, or to the extract\nWhat are the initial true course and distance between positions N5800 W01300 and N6600 E00200?",
    "feedback": "035° - 635 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The evaluation of your plotting work shows a WCA +3° and a drift 3° left",
    "feedback": "Your actual position is on the intended track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the track error angle:\nPlanned track: 197°(T)Actual heading: 213°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 12° left",
    "feedback": "4° right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 135 kt,\nHDG (°T) = 278,\nW/V = 140/20kt\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "283 - 150 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A straight line on a chart 4.89 cm long represents 185 NM.\nThe scale of this chart is approximately :",
    "feedback": "1 : 7 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue course from A to B = 090°,\nTAS = 460 kt, \nW/V = 360/100kt,\nAverage variation = 10°E,\nDeviation = -2°.\nCalculate the compass heading and GS?",
    "feedback": "069° - 448 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aeronautical chart has a published scale of 1 inch = 15 NM. An aircraft is flying on a true heading of 089° with a ground speed of 150 kt. Calculate the chart distance covered by the aircraft in 25 minutes:",
    "feedback": "10,6 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "The scale of a chart is 1:500 000.\nCalculate the distance on this chart which is equivalent to 10 NM on the earth.\nThe distance is approximately:",
    "feedback": "3.7 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the change of longitude between A(45º00'N 163º14'E) and B(31º33'N and 157º 02'E)",
    "feedback": "6º 12' W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the points A (40°S 173°E) and B (60°S 169°W). Which formula gives the Earth convergence between these two positions? (Convergency = change in)",
    "feedback": "Longitude (18°) x sin (50°)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is planning a VFR flight across steep, mountainous terrain. Due to airspace restrictions, the flight will be relatively low above the terrain. Restrictions in VFR navigation in such circumstances can include....",
    "feedback": "a shorter time to see navigation features on the near side of valleys, compared to when flying over a flat landscape"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nDetermine the initial track and distance from position A (N54º53', W006º23') to position B (N55º57', W004º48'):",
    "feedback": "Track 40º(T), 83 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is meant by \"Perihelion\"?",
    "feedback": "The point of the Earth's orbit closest to the Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 350,\nMach 0.80,\nOAT  -55°C. \n\nCalculate the values for TAS and local speed of sound (LSS):",
    "feedback": "461 kt , LSS 576 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart has a constant of the cone of 0.75.  \nThe initial course of a straight line track drawn on this chart from A (40°N  050°W) to B is 043°(T) at A; course at B is 055°(T). \nWhat is the longitude of B?",
    "feedback": "34°W"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying on a westerly great circle track in the southern hemisphere you will:",
    "feedback": "experience an increase in the value of true track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nThe crew of an aircraft coasting in from the North Sea at ST ABBS VOR (N55°54,5' W002°12,4') plans to enter controlled airspace en-route towards ASRUS (N55°03,4' W003°20,8'). What is the true track from ST ABBS to ASRUS, measured at ST ABBS?",
    "feedback": "217°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the approximate distance from waypoint DBU (53°29.0'N, 000°28.6'W) to a waypoint 20 NM north of Bremen airport. The coordinates of Bremen airport are (53°09.0'N, 008°45.0'E):",
    "feedback": "329.4 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "By the term \"transit\" of a heavenly body it is understood that",
    "feedback": "The body is passing the meridian of the observer or another specified meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete line 6 of the 'FLIGHT NAVIGATION LOG', positions 'L' to 'M'.\nWhat is the HDG°(M) and ETA?",
    "feedback": "HDG 075°  -  ETA 1502 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "A day at a place as measured in local mean time starts",
    "feedback": "When the mean sun transits the anti meridian of the place in question"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about meridians is correct?",
    "feedback": "A meridian and its anti-meridian form a complete great circle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Standard Time (ST) and date on the Whitsunday Islands, Australia, if it is 21:30 UTC on the 12th November 2016?",
    "feedback": "07:30, 13th November 2016"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 170 kt,\nHDG(T) = 100°,\nW/V = 350/30kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "109 - 182 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 140 kt, FL 80, OAT +20°C. What is the TAS?",
    "feedback": "164 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A great circle track joins position A (59°S 141°W) and B (61°S 148°W). \nWhat is the difference between the great circle track at A and B?",
    "feedback": "It increases by 6°"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a navigation chart a distance of 49 NM is equal to 7 cm. The scale of the chart is approximately:",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 300 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Polar Stereographic chart, the initial great circle course from A 70°N 060°W to B 70°N 060°E is approximately:",
    "feedback": "030° (T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Assume a Mercator chart.\nThe distance between positions A and B, located on the same parallel and 10° longitude apart, is 6 cm. The scale at the parallel is 1 : 9 260 000.\nWhat is the latitude of A and B?",
    "feedback": "60° N or S"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 150. The QNH, given by a meteorological station at an elevation of 1500 ft is 1000 hPa. OAT = -40°C. The elevation of the highest obstacle along the route is 8000 ft. Use 1hPa = 30 ft.\n\nCalculate the aircraft's clearance above the highest obstacle on this route (rounded off in hundreds of feet):",
    "feedback": "5300 ft"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is climbing from pressure altitude 2500 ft to FL150 with an average TAS of 125 kt. The ground distance that will be covered during climb is 40 NM and the average wind component is 20 kt headwind. What is the required rate of climb?",
    "feedback": "550 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nYou are 55 NM from HONILEY 113.65 HON (N52°21.4' W001°39.8') and 42 NM from POLE HILL 112.1 POL (N53°44.6' W002°06.2'), both distances increasing, on a heading of 086°(M). What is your current position?",
    "feedback": "N53°15' W001°13'"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Northern Hemisphere the rhumb line track from position A to B is 230°, the convergency is 6° and the difference in longitude is 10°. What is the initial rhumb line track from B to A?",
    "feedback": "050°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven the following bearing and range information obtained from DEN HELDER (HDR) VORDME (52º54'N, 004º46'E), what is the aircraft's position?(note: Slant range corrections should be ignored)\nRadial 258ºRange 63 NM",
    "feedback": "52º42'N, 003º04'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 350 with Mach 0.878. OAT = ISA + 4°C. The compressibility factor is 0.939.\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "510 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 190 kt,\nTrue HDG = 085°,\nW/V = 110°(T)/50kt.\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "8°L - 146 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "While proceeding en route, after half of the distance between two waypoints, the aircraft's position is 3 NM left of the desired track. The total distance between the two waypoints is 120 NM.\nUsing the 1 in 60 rule and for the purpose of reaching the active waypoint, the heading should be changed by ....",
    "feedback": "6° to the right"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 227 kt,\nTrack (T) = 316°, \nW/V = 205/15kt.\nCalculate the HDG (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "312 - 232 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a landing on runway 23 (227° magnetic) surface \nW/V reported by the ATIS  is 180/30kt. \nVAR is 13°E. \nCalculate the cross wind component?",
    "feedback": "22 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The parallels on a Lambert Conformal Conic chart are represented by:",
    "feedback": "arcs of concentric circles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the Polar Stereographic Chart is true?",
    "feedback": "The closer to the pole, the more a great circle will coincide with the straight line on the chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:  M 0.80,  OAT -50°C,  FL 330,  GS 490 kt,  VAR 20°W,  Magnetic heading 140°,  Drift is 11° Right.  Calculate the true W/V?",
    "feedback": "020°/95 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two positions plotted on a polar stereographic chart, A (80°N  000°) and B (70°N  102°W) are joined by a straight line whose highest latitude is reached at 035°W.\nAt point B, the true course is:",
    "feedback": "203°"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is layer tinting used to define elevation on a chart?",
    "feedback": "Different colours indicate ranges of elevation, between defined limits"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about the scale of a Lambert projection?",
    "feedback": "The scale reaches its minimum value at the parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "If an aeroplane was to circle around the Earth following parallel 60°N at a ground speed of 480 kt. In order to circle around the Earth along the equator in the same amount of time, it should fly at a ground speed of:",
    "feedback": "960 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which definition describes best the notion \"Poles\"?",
    "feedback": "The Poles are the points of intersection between the earth's axis and the surface of the earth."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue HDG = 206°,\nTAS = 140 kt,\nTrack (T) = 207°,\nGS = 135 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "180/05kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nWhat is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME (N5150.4 W00829.7) to position N5220 W00810?",
    "feedback": "026° - 32 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nPosition 'A' is N00° E100°, \nPosition 'B' is 240°(T), 200 NM from 'A'.\nWhat is the position of 'B'?",
    "feedback": "S01°40' E097°07'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following information is displayed on an Inertial Navigation System:\nGS  520 kt,\nTrue HDG 090°,\nDrift angle 5° right,\nTAS 480 kt.\nSAT (static air temperature) -51°C.\nThe W/V being experienced is:",
    "feedback": "320° / 60 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct definition of geodetic longitude?",
    "feedback": "The angle in the equatorial plane between the line a that connects the Earth's centre with the prime meridian and the line b that connects the centre with the meridian on which the point lies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the orbit of the earth is correct?",
    "feedback": "The orbit of the earth around the sun is an ellipse with the sun at one of the foci."
  },
  {
    "question": "After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH, the aircraft is 3 NM north of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this position, the TH should be:",
    "feedback": "112°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft travels 100 statute miles in 20 MIN, how long does it take to travel 215 NM?",
    "feedback": "50 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following, concerning great circles on a Direct Mercator chart, is correct?",
    "feedback": "With the exception of meridians and the equator, they are curves concave to the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "A great circle intersects the equator at 030°W with a great circle direction of 035°(T). An aircraft tracking the great circle will reach the maximum Northern/Southern latitude in position",
    "feedback": "55°N, 060°E"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying continuously during daylight on an eastbound track on the 12th of the month. What is the date after crossing the International Date Line?",
    "feedback": "11th of the month"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal chart, the given scale differs from the scale at latitudes between the standard parallels. The limitation for this difference is a maximum of ......",
    "feedback": "1% of the scale at the standard parallels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 205 kt,\nHDG (T) = 180°,\nW/V = 240/25kt.\nCalculate the drift and GS?",
    "feedback": "6L - 194 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "TT from A to B is 167°, and the distance is 140 NM. Variation is 12W at A and 14W at B You flight-plan WCA 8L. When the remaining distance to B is 35 NM you notice that your position is 5 NM right of the flight plan track. Since over A you have steered as flight planned. What has the drift been since you were overhead A?",
    "feedback": "10,8 R"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time difference in Local Mean Time between sunrise at positions A (50°N 120°E) and B (50°S 120°E) on the 21st of November is:",
    "feedback": "some hours and the sun rises earlier in B than in A"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Apparent Time\" is",
    "feedback": "Based on the time of transit of the apparent Sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the approximate scale at 22°00'N on a Direct Mercator chart if the scale at 35°00'N is 1:200 000?",
    "feedback": "1:226 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the chart scale is 1 : 500 000, what earth distance would be represented by 7 cm on the chart?",
    "feedback": "35 000 m"
  },
  {
    "question": "The great circle track X - Y measured at x is 319°, and Y 325°\nConsider the following statements:",
    "feedback": "Southern hemisphere, Rhumb line track is 322°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:TALLA (TLA) VORDME (N55º30 W003º21')TURNBERRY (TRN) VORDME (N55º19' W004º47')Aircraft position: 35 NM from TLA and 40 NM from TRN\nFind the geographical position of the aircraft if the DME indications are increasing while following a true track of 180º. (disregard slant range corrections)",
    "feedback": "N54º58' W003º47'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nW/V at arrival aerodrome at MSL is 200°/20kt, W/V at TOD at FL 100 is 260°/50kt. Average track after TOD is 190°. ISA conditions. Descent speed IAS = 150 kt.\n\nFind the GS during the descent:",
    "feedback": "135 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "The lowest speed of the Earth in its orbit is reached, when the Earth is at the following position:",
    "feedback": "Aphelion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given : \nPosition 'A' N60 W020,\nPosition 'B' N60 W021, \nPosition 'C' N59 W020. \nWhat are, respectively, the distances from A to B and from A to C?",
    "feedback": "30 NM and 60 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft descends from its cruising level FL320 to FL040 for commencing an approach. Calculate the average TAS during descent when CAS = 230 kt and OAT = ISA +10°C.",
    "feedback": "309 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nWhat is the radial and DME distance from CRK VOR/DME (N5150.4 W00829.7) to position N5210 W00920?",
    "feedback": "307° - 36 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft on radial 315° at a range of 150 NM from  MYGGENES NDB (N6206 W00732) is at position:",
    "feedback": "N6320 W01205"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTAS = 90 kt,\nHDG (T) = 355°,\nW/V = 120/20kt.\nCalculate the Track (°T) and GS?",
    "feedback": "346 - 102 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 0000 Local Mean Time of an observer:",
    "feedback": "the mean sun is in transit with the observer's anti-meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "for this question use GSPRM chart ED-4\nThe symbol located at the aerodrome of Vilshofen EDMV (N48°38.11' E013°11.74') indicates a (1) .... aerodrome with (2) .... .",
    "feedback": "(1) civil, (2) an electronic aeronautical ground light (aerodrome beacon)"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a direct Mercator projection, the distance measured between two meridians spaced 5° apart at latitude 60°N is 8 cm.\nThe scale of this chart at latitude 60°N is approximately:",
    "feedback": "1 : 3 500 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft is flying overhead RNAV point SHAPP (54°30'00\"N 002°37'38\"W) and has a relative bearing of 282° to CARLISLE NDB (328 CL, 54°56'25\"N 002°48'20\"W). What is the magnetic heading of the aircraft, if the magnetic variation is 2°W at CL NDB?",
    "feedback": "067°(M)"
  },
  {
    "question": "For descent calculations, the wind direction and velocity used is:",
    "feedback": "The wind direction and velocity at the altitude 1/2 of the descent altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft takes off from an airport located on the 160°E meridian at 0243 LMT and flies for 3 hours to a destination airport located on the 170°W meridian.\nAt what time LMT does it land at its destination?",
    "feedback": "0743"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft departs point A (26°06'N 004°11'E) and flies directly south for 500 NM to point B. From point B, the aircraft flies directly east for 500 NM to point C. The coordinates of point C are ....",
    "feedback": "17°46'N 012°56'E"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL370 is required to commence descent at 120 NM from a VOR and to cross the facility at FL130. If the mean GS for the descent is 288 kt, the minimum rate of descent required is:",
    "feedback": "960 FT/MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nHDG 230°T\nGS 340 kt\nW/V 270°/40 kt\n\nCalculate the Track and TAS:",
    "feedback": "Track = 226°, TAS = 370 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given time difference: 9 hours 20 minutes. Calculate the corresponding difference in longitude:",
    "feedback": "140°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"Aphelion\" is used to describe",
    "feedback": "The situation when the distance between the sun and the earth is at its longest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nThe track (°M) and distance (NM) between BELFAST 117.2 BEL (N54°39.5' W006°13.8') and MACHRIHANISH 116.0 MAC (N55°25.8' W005°39.0') is:",
    "feedback": "028° and 50 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "At 47° North the chart distance between meridians 10° apart is 5 inches. \nThe scale of the chart at 47° North approximates:",
    "feedback": "1 : 6 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "The magnetic meridian in a position is",
    "feedback": "The horizontal direction of the Earth's magnetic field in that position, toward the\nmagnetic north pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about crossing the date line?",
    "feedback": "When approaching the date line from the east (on a westerly heading) one day is gained"
  },
  {
    "question": "The initial great circle track from A to B is 080° and the rhumb line track is 083°. What is the initial great circle track from B to A and in which hemisphere are the two positions located?",
    "feedback": "266° and in the northern hemisphere"
  },
  {
    "question": "After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH, the aircraft is 2.5 NM south of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this position, the TH should be:",
    "feedback": "081°"
  },
  {
    "question": ".\nRefer to the table\nAt what UTC time is the end of the Evening Civil Twilight on the 19th October 2017 at Bodø airport in Norway (67°16'N 014°22'E)?",
    "feedback": "16:13 UTC"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information and using a mechanical computer, what is the change in CAS required to reduce the TAS of an aircraft from 150 kt to 105 kt?\nPressure altitude: 7000 ftOAT: -8°C",
    "feedback": "41 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Contour lines on aeronautical maps and charts connect points :",
    "feedback": "having the same elevation above sea level"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nThe following bearing and range information obtained from HONILEY VORDME HON (52°21'N, 001°40'W) is given:\nRadial 334°Range 44 NM\nFind the current position of the aircraft:(note: slant range corrections should be ignored)",
    "feedback": "53°00'N, 002°13'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "Estimated Time of Departure A (15°15.0'N, 072°06.0'W) on 12 March is 01:00 ST (ST = UTC - 5hrs).\nEstimated Time of Arrival B (55°18.0'N, 005°45.0'E) 16:15 ST on the same date (ST = UTC + 1 hr).\nAccording to the Jeppesen table sunset at B occurs at 18:20.\nCalculate the flight time from A to B and the time between arrival and sunset at B.",
    "feedback": "09h15m and 02h42m"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fuel flow per HR is 31 US-GAL, total fuel on board is 260 Liter. What is the endurance?",
    "feedback": "2 HR 13 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Air Almanac the highest time difference listed for difference between UTC and \nStandard time is maximum",
    "feedback": "13 hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the routes represents the greatest difference between the rhumb line and the great circle on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "GH"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft follows a great circle in the northern hemisphere. At a certain moment the aircraft is in the position on the great circle where the great circle direction is 270°(T). Continuing on the great circle the:",
    "feedback": "track angle will decrease and the latitude will decrease"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 19Surface wind from the tower: 20530KT\nWhat is the XWC?",
    "feedback": "8 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider any two positions with a difference in longitude of 7°. The proportional difference between the rhumb line distance and the great circle distance between the two positions increases with....",
    "feedback": "increasing latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the two smallest map scales, given the following:\n1) 1 : 1 000 0002) 10 cm = 10 NM3) 1 inch = 10 NM4) 1 inch = 60 NM5) 1 : 110 000",
    "feedback": "1, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The distance between the parallels of latitude 17º23'S and 23º59'N is",
    "feedback": "2482 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nWhich feature is shown on the chart at position 55º11'N, 004º10'W?",
    "feedback": "New Galloway NDB/Locator"
  },
  {
    "question": "After 15 minutes of flying with the planned TAS and TH, the aircraft is 3 NM south of the intended track and 2.5 NM ahead of the dead reckoning position. To reach destination B from this position, the TH should be:",
    "feedback": "078°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 235 kt,\nHDG (T) = 076°\nW/V = 040/40kt.\nCalculate the drift angle and GS?",
    "feedback": "7R - 204 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct definition of latitude of a position on the earth?",
    "feedback": "Latitude is the angle between the plane of the equator and the line from the centre of the earth to the position."
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the true heading and ground speed, using mental dead reckoning. Given:\nTrack: 260°(T)TAS: 270 ktW/V: 31035KT",
    "feedback": "TH 266°, GS 249 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Transferring position lines (LOP):An aircraft should follow a true course 120°, given TAS 100 KT and W/V 360/50. It obtains position lines at 1400, 1403, 1406 hours.",
    "feedback": "1 LOP is transferred by 11.6 NM, 1 LOP by 5.8 NM, the third one is not transferred"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate the ground distance for a climb from pressure altitude 2500 ft to FL140, given the information below:\nAverage TAS: 125 ktAverage headwind component: 20 ktRate of climb: 675 ft/min.",
    "feedback": "29.8 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\ntrue track 352°\nvariation 11° W\ndeviation is -5°\ndrift 10°R.\nCalculate the compass heading?",
    "feedback": "358°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying from SALCO to BERRY HEAD on Magnetic Track 007°. At 1000 UTC the relative bearing of locator PY is 311°. At 1003 UTC the relative bearing of locator PY is 266°.\nCalculate the true bearing of locator PY at 1003 UTC from the aircraft, given that:\nTAS: 445 ktW/V: 050°(T)/40 ktVariation: 5°WDeviation: +2°",
    "feedback": "272°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:CAS = 190 kt Pressure Altitude = 9000 ft  Calculate Mach number:",
    "feedback": "0.34"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert Conformal Conic chart earth convergency is most accurately represented at the:",
    "feedback": "parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "For flight planning purposes, a navigation chart with a Lambert conformal conic projection is used. The constant of the cone for this chart is 0.83. A straight line is drawn from the current position (50°N 175°E) to the destination.\nAt the current position, the track to the destination is 073°(T), the course at the destination is 078°(T).\nWhat is the longitude of the destination?",
    "feedback": "179°W"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft departing A(N40º 00´ E080º 00´) flies a constant true track of 270º at a ground speed of 120 kt.  What are the coordinates of the position reached in 6 HR?",
    "feedback": "N40º 00´ E064º 20´"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are flying at FL 80 and the air temperature is ISA+15. What CAS is required to make \nTAS 240 Kt?",
    "feedback": "206 Kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic projection, with two standard parallels:",
    "feedback": "the scale is only correct along the standard parallels"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft starts a descent at FL130 and descends to FL060. The CAS during the descent is 130 kt in ISA conditions. For dead reckoning, what is the TAS to be considered during the descent?",
    "feedback": "153 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the sun's declination is northerly",
    "feedback": "The daylight period is shorter in the southern hemisphere than the northern"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the result when vector 1 is added to vector 2?",
    "feedback": "Vector A"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can be said about the area represented on a Lambert projection which lies between the two standard parallels of the chart?",
    "feedback": "In this area the scale of the chart differs less than 1% from the state scale of the chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL120, IAS 200kt, OAT -5° and wind component +30kt, is required to reduce speed in order to cross a reporting point 5 MIN later than planned.  Assuming flight conditions do not change, when 100 NM from the reporting point IAS should be reduced to:",
    "feedback": "159 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What wind vector shall be used for calculating the average GS for a descent from FL200 to the Initial Approach Fix (IAF) at a pressure altitude of 4000 ft?\nW/VMSL: 22015KT5000 ft: 24025KTFL100: 25035KTFL150: 25045KTFL200: 26035KTFL240: 300125KT",
    "feedback": "25039KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nMagnetic track = 075°,\nHDG = 066°(M),\nVAR = 11°E,\nTAS = 275 kt\nAircraft flies 48 NM in 10 MIN.\nCalculate the true W/V °?",
    "feedback": "340°/45 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the only true great circle on the surface of the WGS-84 ellipsoid?",
    "feedback": "The great circle that is coincident with the equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: TAS = 480 kt, OAT = ISA +8°C, FL 410.  Calculate the Mach Number:",
    "feedback": "0.82"
  },
  {
    "question": "If one minute of latitude along the parallel of 55°N is 3.1 mm on a direct Mercator chart, what is the scale of the chart at 40°N?",
    "feedback": "1 : 457 650"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the danger about power lines, when flying VFR over a snowy area?",
    "feedback": "The represent a danger when power lines cross the valley"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on the shape of the earth",
    "feedback": "It is slightly flattened at the poles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 08Surface wind from the tower: 12520KT\nWhat is the XWC?",
    "feedback": "15 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "The highest value of longitude is found",
    "feedback": "At Greenwich anti meridian"
  },
  {
    "question": "A planned route has a distance of 150 NM and a true course of 097°.\nThe planned ground speed is 132 kt, the true heading is 101°.\nAfter 23 minutes en-route a fix is overflown that is 57 NM away from the departure point and has a cross track distance from the course line of 4 NM right of course.\nCalculate the true track and the actual ground speed flown:",
    "feedback": "true track 101°, ground speed 148 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: TAS 168 kt, FL 85, OAT -10°C. What is the CAS?",
    "feedback": "150 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue HDG = 054°,\nTAS = 450 kt,\nTrack (T) = 059°,\nGS = 416 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "010/50kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given that you are to travel from location A (30°S 168°E) to location B (8°S 175°W) in October, you expect the duration of daylight at location B to be (1) .... than at location A, and the rate of change of apparent solar day to be (2) ....",
    "feedback": "(1) shorter, (2) slower"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nYour distance is 58 NM from POLE HILL 112.1 POL (N53°44.6' W002°06.2') and on the 052° radial. What is your position?",
    "feedback": "N54°23'N W000°47'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on Sunrise and Sunset",
    "feedback": "At equator sunrise and sunset occur at quite regular times throughout the year"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM - Chart E(LO)2\nWhat is the magnetic track and distance from MACHRIHANISH 116.0 MAC (N55°25.8' W005°39.0') to waypoint CLYDE (N55°57.8' W004°47.5)?",
    "feedback": "046° and 43 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The angle between the plane of the ecliptic and the plane of equator is approximately :",
    "feedback": "23.5°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on the great circle and the rhumb line running through the same two positions",
    "feedback": "All statements are correct"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the ground speed (GS) of an aircraft travelling from WINDFARM to WIMEREUX, given that it arrives at WIMEREUX at 14:42.",
    "feedback": "125 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "For climb calculations, the wind direction and velocity used is:",
    "feedback": "At the altitude two thirds of the cruising altitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Grivation\"",
    "feedback": "Is the sum of Grid convergence and variation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue course 300°\ndrift 8°R\nvariation 10°W\ndeviation -4° \nCalculate the compass heading?",
    "feedback": "306°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Parallels of latitude on a Direct Mercator chart are :",
    "feedback": "parallel straight lines unequally spaced"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a sunrise/sunset table given for the 28th of June at a certain latitude, sunrise is given as 0239 and sunset is given as 2127.\n\nWhat is the latitude?",
    "feedback": "60°N"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert conformal projection the chart convergency between two positions depends on:",
    "feedback": "the difference in longitude of the two positions and the latitude of the parallel of origin"
  },
  {
    "question": "The equivalent of 70 m/sec is approximately:",
    "feedback": "136 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the chart extract.\nAt 10:07 you make a note of your position over the intersection of highways A3 and A92 (N48°49.0' E012°56.3'). Consider the DR positions DR-1 to DR-4 shown on the chart. Given the following information, determine your DR position at 10:19.\nTAS: 107 ktWind: 11035 KTTrue Heading: 130°",
    "feedback": "DR-3 (N48°37.3' E013°10.9')"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about crossing the date line?",
    "feedback": "When approaching the date line from the west (on an easterly heading) one day is lost"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a lightship?",
    "feedback": "19"
  },
  {
    "question": "When flying a day VFR flight at low level, using checkpoints on a 1:500 000 map, the most suitable features are.....",
    "feedback": "ones that are tall and prominent, such as towers"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is descending down a 6% slope whilst maintaining a GS of 300 kt.\nThe rate of descent of the aircraft is approximately:",
    "feedback": "1800 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 435 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 1920 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "4 HR 25 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The great circle distance between A (30°N 010°W) and B (30°N 020°E) is 1554.3 NM. The difference between the great circle distance and the rhumb line distance between C (40°N 010°W) and D (40°N 020°E) is:",
    "feedback": "greater than 4.5 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies from point A to point B, which is 45 NM away. After 7 minutes or 12 NM, the aircraft is located 3 NM left off track. What heading change is required to fly directly to point B?",
    "feedback": "20°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the Almanac extract:\nWhat is the duration of evening civil twilight (ECT) on the 11th October 2017 at Jinzhou Xiaolingzi Airport, China (N41°06' E121°04')?",
    "feedback": "28 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the great circle distance between A (85N, 172°W) and  B (85°N, 008°E)?",
    "feedback": "600 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is planning for a VFR cross-country flight, using visual checkpoints. Which of the following would be the most suitable checkpoint?",
    "feedback": "A feature that contrasts with its natural surroundings"
  },
  {
    "question": "A great circle track is drawn on a Lambert chart between positions A and B in the Northern Hemisphere. The great circle true track at position A is measured at 070°, while at position B, it is measured as 076°.\nIf the parallel of origin of the Lambert chart is 37°, what is the longitude difference between positions A and B?",
    "feedback": "009°58'"
  },
  {
    "question": "To establish a track plot you need",
    "feedback": "At least two pinpoints or fixes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The time it takes for the Earth to complete one orbit around the Sun is",
    "feedback": "365 days 5 hours 48 minutes 45 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given : Indicated altitude 9000 FT, OAT -32°C, CAS 200 kt. QNH 1013. What is the TAS?",
    "feedback": "215 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 300\nOAT = - 45°C\nIAS = 260 kt\nInstrument and position error to be neglected\nCompressibility factor = 0.96\n\nCalculate the True Air Speed taking compressibility into account:",
    "feedback": "408 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Position A = 56°00.0'S, 163°57.2'EPosition B = 56°00.0'S, 171°47.4'W\nFor the route from A to be the.....",
    "feedback": "great circle direction at B is 080°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The great circle distance between position A (59°34.1'N 008°08.4'E) and B (30°25.9'N 171°51.6'W) is:",
    "feedback": "5 400 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "When it is 1200 Standard Time in Queensland (Australia) on the 10th July (UTC+10), the Standard Time in Hawaii, USA (UTC-10) is (assume that daylight savings time does to apply):",
    "feedback": "16:00 ST 9th July"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the parallel of origin for a Direct Mercator projection?",
    "feedback": "The equator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: \nTrue HDG = 035°,\nTAS = 245 kt,\nTrack (T) = 046°,\nGS = 220 kt.\nCalculate the W/V?",
    "feedback": "340/50kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the Earth's ellipsoid one degree of latitude near the equator is:",
    "feedback": "less than 60 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: TAS 140 kt, FL 80, OAT +20°C. What is the CAS?",
    "feedback": "120 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on sunset:",
    "feedback": "Sunset is the time when the observer at sea level see the last part of the sun disappear below the horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nFL 390\nOAT = ISA + 15°C\nCAS = 240 kt\n\nCalculate the TAS, assuming a compressibility factor of 0.96:",
    "feedback": "468 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nAirport elevation is 1000 ft. \nQNH is 988 hPa.\nWhat is the approximate airport pressure altitude?\n(Assume 1 hPa = 27 FT)",
    "feedback": "1680 FT"
  },
  {
    "question": "Consider the following statements on the properties of a great circle:",
    "feedback": "The great circle running through two positions on the surface of the earth, is the shortest distance between these two positions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates the boundary of advisory airspace?",
    "feedback": "15"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is following the 45°N parallel of latitude. The track followed is a:",
    "feedback": "Rhumb line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given an intended track 270°, W/V 040/40, TAS 180 MPH",
    "feedback": "The air position is north of  the intended track"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, calculate the rate of descent (ROD) for an aircraft that is approaching the destination after a descent from FL180 to pressure altitude 3000 ft.\nGround distance during the descent: 25 NMAverage TAS: 130 ktAverage tailwind component: 30 kt",
    "feedback": "1600 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "The scale on a Lambert conformal conic chart :",
    "feedback": "is constant along a parallel of latitude"
  },
  {
    "question": "Two vectors of different magnitude are added. What information can be determined from the resultant vector?",
    "feedback": "Magnitude and direction"
  },
  {
    "question": "For navigation a Polar Stereographic chart is used. \nThe straight line between A (75°00'.0S, 166°00'.0E) and B (78°00'.0S, 154°00'.0E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle of the rhumbline is 223°.\n\nCalculate the direction (°T) of the straight line in position B.",
    "feedback": "229°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term \"Ellipsoid\" may be used to describe",
    "feedback": "The shape of the earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a Direct Mercator projection chart, the scale at 23°N is 1 : 2 761 515. What is the scale of the same chart at 56°N?",
    "feedback": "1 : 1 677 579"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 345 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 3560 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "10 HR 19 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart at latitude 15°S, a certain length represents a distance of 120 NM on the earth. \nThe same length on the chart will represent on the earth, at latitude 10°N, a distance of :",
    "feedback": "122.3 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "On an aeronautical chart it is common that",
    "feedback": "The exact scale vary within the chart"
  },
  {
    "question": "Plotting positions on charts by dead reckoning (DR) may be required ....",
    "feedback": "during a flight with limited equipment and few navigational aids"
  },
  {
    "question": "While flying in the Northern hemisphere, an aircraft has a VOR RMI reading of 285°(M) to XYZ VOR. Given the following information, what bearing should be plotted from the VOR to the aircraft on a Mercator chart?\nVariation at the aircraft: 4°EVariation at XYZ VOR: 8°EEarth convergence between aircraft and XYZ VOR: 6°",
    "feedback": "116°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which aeronautical chart symbol indicates a Way-point?",
    "feedback": "8"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which of the following chart projections is it NOT possible to represent the north or south poles?",
    "feedback": "Direct Mercator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: CAS 324 kt, FL 290, OAT -46°C. What is the TAS?",
    "feedback": "487 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft at FL330 is required to commence descent \nwhen 65 NM from a VOR and to cross the VOR at FL100. \nThe mean GS during the descent is 330 kt. \nWhat is the minimum rate of descent required?",
    "feedback": "1950 FT/MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "While flying on a heading of 185°(M) in the Northern hemisphere, an aircraft measures the relative bearing of ONO NDB on an Relative Bearing Indicator (RBI) as 065°R. Given the following information, what bearing should be plotted from the beacon to the aircraft on a Lambert chart?\nVariation at the aircraft: 6°EVariation at the station: 4°EChart convergence between the aircraft and the NDB: 8°",
    "feedback": "068°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "The aircraft position is (55°30'N 012°00'E). An NDB is located in position (55°30'N 020°00'E). A conical chart with standard parallels at 40° N and 50°N is used.\n\nWhat is the direction of the line of position in this chart from the NDB?",
    "feedback": "273°"
  },
  {
    "question": "The equator is located",
    "feedback": "On the surface of the earth, being a circle whose plane is perpendicular to the axis of the earth and cutting through the centre of the earth."
  },
  {
    "question": "According the Kepler’s First Law planets travel around the sun in an elliptical orbit. Consider the following statements:",
    "feedback": "The sun is at one of the foci. Aphelion is the position in the elliptical orbit furthest from the sun"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nThe following bearing and range information obtained from HONILEY VORDME HON (52°21'N, 001°40'W) is given:\nRadial 034°Range 44 NM\nFind the current position of the aircraft:(note: slant range corrections should be ignored)",
    "feedback": "52°59'N, 000°59'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "The length of the apparent solar day varies continuously throughout the year. This is caused by:",
    "feedback": "the tilt of the earth's axis and the elliptical orbit of the earth around the sun."
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 480 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 5360 NM.\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "11 HR 10 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart, meridians are:",
    "feedback": "parallel, equally spaced, vertical straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 370 kt,\nTrue HDG = 181°,\nW/V = 095°(T)/35kt.\nCalculate the true track and GS?",
    "feedback": "186 - 370 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of aeronautical chart symbol No. 12?",
    "feedback": "Hazard Beacon"
  },
  {
    "question": "A line from a navigation log for a VFR flight is shown above, for a leg starting over the VORDME station CWD. The aircraft flies over CWD at 10:06 UTC and turn to the correct heading and speed. At 10:21 UTC the pilot takes a position fix off CWD and the aircraft is on the 247° radial at a DME distance of 24 NM.\nWhat is the approximate cross-track error?",
    "feedback": "1.6 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft flies the following rhumb line tracks and distances \nfrom position 04°00'N 030°00'W :\n600 NM South, \nthen 600 NM East, \nthen 600 NM North, \nthen 600 NM West.\nThe final position of the aircraft is:",
    "feedback": "04°00'N 029°58'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "A is at longitude 01230E and B is at longitude 04315E. LMT in B is 1749. \nWhat is the LMT in A?",
    "feedback": "1546"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nDistance A to B = 120 NM,\nAfter 30 NM aircraft is 3 NM to the left of course.\nWhat heading alteration should be made in order to arrive at point 'B'?",
    "feedback": "8° right"
  },
  {
    "question": "The tank capacity of an aircraft is 310 US GAL. Fuel specific gravity is 0,78 kg/litre.\nThe tanks are now 3/4 full. You want to refuel so that total fuel will be 850 kg.\nHow much fuel will you have to refuel? Answer in pounds.",
    "feedback": "360 LB"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the aeronautical chart symbols indicates a VORTAC?",
    "feedback": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: ILS GP angle = 3.5 DEG, GS = 150 kt. What is the approximate rate of descent?",
    "feedback": "875 FT/MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "The constant of cone of a Lambert conformal conic chart is quoted as 0.3955. \n At what latitude on the chart is earth convergency correctly represented?",
    "feedback": "23°18'"
  },
  {
    "question": "The forces acting upon the compass needle in a stand-by compass in an aircraft, are",
    "feedback": "The Earth's magnetic field, the aircraft magnetic field and the effects of attitude and movement of the aircraft"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft starts to climb from 4000 ft to 8000 ft with a ground speed of 220 kt and with a constant rate of climb of 1600 ft/min. Given the following information, how long will it take to climb and what ground distance will be covered?\nAverage climb TAS: 240 ktWind at 8000 ft: 20045KTApproximate track during the climb: 250°T",
    "feedback": "2.5 min; 8.7 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nYou are flying close to Walney Island Airport, EGNL, 54°7'42.83\"N, 3°15'7.76\"W) on a heading of 085°(T). The magnetic bearing to WL NDB is 121°, the co-located DME gives a distance of 30 NM. What is your aircraft position ?(disregard DME slant range distance)",
    "feedback": "54°21'N, 004°00'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ratio between the litre and the US-GAL ?",
    "feedback": "1 US-GAL equals 3.78 litres"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the duration of daylight is true?",
    "feedback": "Close to the equinoxes the influence of latitude on the duration of daylight is at its smallest"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, determine the track error angle:\nPlanned track: 255°(T)Actual heading: 258°(T)Actual in-flight drift: 3° left",
    "feedback": "0°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Twilight",
    "feedback": "Are the periods before sunrise and after sunset when the light is lower than when the\nsun is above the horizon"
  },
  {
    "question": "The chart that is generally used for navigation in polar areas is based on a:",
    "feedback": "Stereographical projection"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ISA temperature value at FL 330?",
    "feedback": "-51°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the tables below:\n\nThe GMT of sunrise at (66°48'N 095°26'W) on 27th of January is?",
    "feedback": "15:49 GMT"
  },
  {
    "question": "According the Kepler’s First Law planets travel around the sun in an elliptical orbit. Consider the following statements:",
    "feedback": "The sun is at one of the 2 foci"
  },
  {
    "question": "For descent planning from 15000 feet MSL to 3000 feet MSL, a glide path angle of 3° shall be flown. The ground speed at 15000 feet is 180 kt, the ground speed at 3000 feet is 150 kt.\nTo maintain a glide path angle of 3°, the rate of descent will:",
    "feedback": "Decrease from 900 ft/min to 750 ft/min."
  },
  {
    "question": "The main purpose of DR navigation is:",
    "feedback": "to obtain, with reasonable accuracy, the aircraft's position between fixes or in the absence of fixes"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a polar stereographic chart the scale at the pole is 1 : 5 mill. Calculate the scale of the chart at 6500N:",
    "feedback": "1 : 4,766 mill"
  },
  {
    "question": "The TAS is 240 kt and the wind is blowing 30° from the right of your track at 60 kt. Determine the groundspeed, using Mental Dead Reckoning (no aids allowed):",
    "feedback": "186 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nPlanned heading is 217° (T), and after 40 NM along track the aircraft position is fixed 4 NM left of planned track. What heading is required to fly direct to the next waypoint which is another 79 NM down track?",
    "feedback": "TKE = 6°, CA = 3° Heading required = 226°"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator, rhumb lines are:",
    "feedback": "straight lines"
  },
  {
    "question": "The evaluation of the differences between DR (dead reckoned) positions and actual positions (fixes) can refine flight performance and navigation.\nWhich of the following factors affect the accuracy of a DR position?\n1) The accuracy of the last positive fix2) The accuracy with which heading has been maintained3) The accuracy with which air speed has been maintained4) The accuracy of our estimate of the wind affecting the aircraft",
    "feedback": "1, 2, 3, 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "The departure is from an airfield at 2000 ft elevation. Temperature at the field is +20°C, QNH 1013 hPa. The plan is to climb to FL 290, where outside air temperature is -40°C. The CAS in the climb is 180 kt, compressibility negligible.\n\nThe average TAS in the climb is:",
    "feedback": "249 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is at position (53°N 006°W) and has a landmark at position (52°47'N 004°45'W), with a relative bearing of 060°.\n\nGiven:\nCompass Heading = 051°\nVariation = 16°W\nDeviation = 2°E\n\nWhat is the true bearing of the position line to be plotted from the landmark to the aircraft on a Lambert Chart with standard parallels at 37°N and 65°N?",
    "feedback": "278°"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is following the flight log, and during the flight the wind has been as forecast. Between the M20 junction and the DET VOR, the pilot diverts from the route to avoid low clouds. Once past the cloud the pilot is able to obtain a visual fix, finding that the aircraft is 15 NM along the route from the M20 junction but approximately 2,5 NM to the left of that route. By the 1:60 rule, the magnetic heading to fly to arrive at the DET VOR is ....",
    "feedback": "296°"
  },
  {
    "question": "UTC  stands for",
    "feedback": "Universal Time Co-ordinated"
  },
  {
    "question": "At latitude 60°N the scale of a Mercator projection is 1 : 5 000 000. The length on the chart between 'C'  N60°  E008° and 'D'  N60° W008° is:",
    "feedback": "17.8 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Mean time\" has been introduced in order to",
    "feedback": "Introduce a constant measurement of time, independent of the daily variations in the movement of the Sun as observed from the Earth"
  },
  {
    "question": "A pilot is flying the route depicted. After completing the first leg, the pilot realizes that the actual wind conditions differ from the forecast used for flight planning. On the leg between the Fruges Windfarm and Wimereux, the pilot checks the aircraft's satellite navigation system and notes a ground speed of 115 kt. When should the pilot expect to arrive at the turning point over Wimereux?",
    "feedback": "14:43"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:\nDistance to go = 84 NMGS = 264  kt\nWhat is the ETA?",
    "feedback": "19 min"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft descends from FL 220 to FL 40 for the final approach.\nCAS = 220 kt\nOAT = ISA +10°C\n\nThe average TAS in the descent is:",
    "feedback": "273 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "for this question use Jeppesen GSPRM chart AT(HI)5:\nAn aircraft is over the dead reckoning position (N74 00.0, E015 00.0). In this position the magnetic bearing obtained of Bjornoya NDB BJO (N74 30.1, E019 05.2) reads 056°.\nWhat is the true bearing of the position line to be plotted from the NDB on this Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "249°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the following information, what would be the average ground speed used to plan a climb from MSL (1013 hPa) to FL270?\nCAS: 280 ktISA Deviation: +5°CTrue Track: 045°\nW/VMSL: 27510KT5000 ft: 28020KT10000 ft: 30020KT15000 ft: 31045KT20000 ft: 31045KT25000 ft: 31055KT30000 ft: 33055KT",
    "feedback": "371 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the formula used to calculate convergency between two positions relatively close to each other?\nConvergency = Difference in ....",
    "feedback": "longitude x sin (mean latitude)"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Lambert Conformal chart the distance between meridians 5° apart along latitude 37° North is 9 cm. The scale of the chart at that parallel approximates:",
    "feedback": "1 : 5 000 000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Position A is at latitude 33º45'N and position B is at latitude 14º25'N. What is the change in latitude between A and B?",
    "feedback": "19º20'"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is making a VFR cross-country flight at low level. The flight involves at least four visual checkpoints on the route.\nWhich option indicates the most suitable type of checkpoint?",
    "feedback": "Look for distinctive features such as a railway line to lead into a checkpoint"
  },
  {
    "question": "The highest speed of the Earth in its orbit is reached, when the Earth is at the following position:",
    "feedback": "Perihelion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Great circle from P to Q measured at P=095°\nSouthern hemisphere\nConversion angle P - Q =7°\nWhat is the rhumb line track P - Q?",
    "feedback": "088"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many degrees has the mean sun moved along the celestial equator in 8 hours and 8 minutes?",
    "feedback": "122°"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nAn aircraft is en-route from position A (N55°43' W004°17') to position B (N54°53' W002°53').\nUsing this information, determine the initial track from position A to position B and also the distance from position A to the point of crossing latitude N55°00'.",
    "feedback": "Track 136°(T), distance 58 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Mu'a, Tonga Islands, is situated at (21°11'S 175°07'W). In the Air Almanac the Standard Time of Tonga Islands is listed as UTC + 13.\n\nFor August 21st the sunrise table in the Air Almanac shows:\n20°S: 06:18\n30°S: 06:28\n\nWhat is the Standard Time of sunrise at Mu'a?",
    "feedback": "06:59 on August 22nd"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft travels 2.4 statute miles in 47 seconds.  What is its ground speed?",
    "feedback": "160 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: GS = 236 kt.\nDistance from A to B = 354 NM\nWhat is the time from A to B?",
    "feedback": "1 HR 30 MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "Preparing a chart for use of grid means",
    "feedback": "Selecting a meridian on the chart and drawing lines on the chart, parallel to the meridian selected"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nGiven:RWY 18Surface wind from the tower: 21315KT\nWhat is the XWC?",
    "feedback": "8 KT"
  },
  {
    "question": "You are required to descend from FL 230 to FL 50 over a distance of 32 NM in 7 minutes. \nWhat is the required Rate of Descent when you expect WC-25 during the descent?",
    "feedback": "2570 ft/min"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to the Almanac extract:\nWhat is the duration of evening civil twilight (ECT) on the 11th October 2017 at Guangzhou Balyon Airport, China (N23°24' E113°18')?",
    "feedback": "23 minutes"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart with standard parallels at 54°N and 59°N is used for navigation.\nThe straight line between A (55°00.0'N, 165°00.0'E) and B (58°00.0'N, ??°??.?'E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle along the straight line at A is 301° and at B is 292°.\n\nCalculate the difference in longitude from A to B:",
    "feedback": "010°47.6'W"
  },
  {
    "question": "\"Kilometre\" is defined as",
    "feedback": "A 1/10000 part of the meridian length from Equator to the pole"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given: Waypoint 1.  60°S 030°W\n           Waypoint 2.  60°S 020°W\nWhat will be the approximate latitude shown on the display unit of an inertial navigation system at longitude 025°W?",
    "feedback": "060°06'S"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, VFR chart ED-4\nA direct flight is planned from Sonnen EDPS (N48°41' E013°42') to Vilshofen EDMV (N48°38' E013°12'). The true track from EDPS to EDMV is (1) ...... and the distance is (2) ...... NM.",
    "feedback": "(1) 262°, (2) 20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Calculate by means of Mental Dead Reckoning (MDR) - no aids allowed\nPlanned heading is 182° (T), and after 20 NM along track the aircraft position is fixed 1 NM right of planned track. What heading is required to regain track in approximately the same time as has taken to the fix position?",
    "feedback": "TKE = 3° Heading required = 176° (T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the tailwind component with the following information given, using trigonometry:\nRunway 33Surface wind (from the tower): 19015KTVariation: 20°W",
    "feedback": "11.5 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is following a descent profile of 4 degrees. What is the requested rate of descent at FL 200, assuming a CAS 280 KT, standard temperatures and 30 KT tailwind?",
    "feedback": "2850 FT / MIN"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aerodrome is located at Mean Sea Level and its traffic pattern altitude is at 1500 ft. Given the following information, to reach downwind at the traffic pattern altitude, a 3° path descent must be initiated at (1) .... prior to downwind, and it will last for (2) ....\nCruise altitude: 4500 ftAverage rate of descent for a 3° path: 850 ft/min",
    "feedback": "(1) 10 NM; (2) 3 minutes 30 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying from SALCO to BERRY HEAD on Magnetic Track 007°, TAS 445 kts. The wind is 050°(T)/40 kts, variation 5°W, deviation +2°.\nAt 1000 UTC the RB of locator PY is 311°. At 1003 UTC the RB of locator PY is 266°.\nCalculate the distance of the aircraft from locator PY at 1003 UTC.",
    "feedback": "21 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "Before departure the ATIS at Buenos Aires airfield announces:\nTake-off Runway 35\nW/V 050°/20-30kt\nTemperature + 20°C\nQNH 1000 hPa\n\nOn the airport chart for Buenos Aires the direction of runway 35 is given as 347° and the magnetic variation is 5°W.\n\nCalculate the maximum cross wind component for departure:",
    "feedback": "27 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "For an aircraft flying from a departure aerodrome with latitude 37°S to a destination aerodrome with latitude 08°S during October, the length of the daylight is (1) .... and the twilight lasts (2) .... at the destination.",
    "feedback": "(1) shorter, (2) less"
  },
  {
    "question": "Refer to Jeppesen GSPRM, Chart E(LO)2\nGiven:CONNAUGHT (CON) 117.4 MHz, 53º55'N, 008º49'WWAYPOINT A, 54º00'N, 008º00'W\nCalculate the radial and distance of WAYPOINT A from CON:",
    "feedback": "084º, 30 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "The nominal scale of a Lambert conformal conic chart is the:",
    "feedback": "scale at the standard parallels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTAS = 480 kt\nOAT = ISA - 10°C\nFL 300\n\nCalculate the Mach number:",
    "feedback": "0.83"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nTrue Track 245°\nDrift 5° right\nVariation 3°E\nCompass heading 242°\n\nCalculate the deviation:",
    "feedback": "5°W"
  },
  {
    "question": "An approximate equation for calculation conversion angle is",
    "feedback": "CA=0,5 x dlong x sin [mean lat]"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given:\nConditions: ISATop of descent (TOD): FL130Wind at the TOD: 28045KTDescent altitude: 1000 ft/AMSLWind at 1000 ft/AMSL: 23015KTIAS and track during descent: 170 kt/220°\nWhat is the approximate ground speed (GS) during the descent?",
    "feedback": "165 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the headwind component to the closest full knot, given the information below, using trigonometry:\nRunway 01Surface wind (from the tower): 30026KTVariation: 13°W",
    "feedback": "9 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Seasons are due to the:",
    "feedback": "inclination of the polar axis with the ecliptic plane"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the figures most accurately represents the great circle route from A to B on a Polar Stereographic chart?",
    "feedback": "Figure B"
  },
  {
    "question": "An aircraft is flying at FL 370 at a speed of Mach 0.915. OAT = ISA - 4°C. The compressibility factor is 0.942.\n\nCalculate the TAS:",
    "feedback": "520 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using a mechanical computer, determine the TAS of the aircraft, given the following information:\nAltitude: 3000 ftQNH: 1046 hPaOAT: +10°CCAS: 154 kt",
    "feedback": "158 kt"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of aeronautical chart symbol No. 19?",
    "feedback": "Lightship"
  },
  {
    "question": "A route is flown from (85°S 100°E) to (85°S 140°W). At 180°E/W the True Track (TT) on a Polar Stereographic chart, whose grid is aligned with the Greenwich meridian, is respectively:",
    "feedback": "070°(T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "A Lambert conformal conic chart with standard parallels at 54°S and 59°S is used for navigation.\nThe straight line between A (55°00.0'S, 165°00.0'E) and B (58°00.0'S, 154°00.0'E) is drawn in this chart. The True Track angle along the straight line in A is 239°.\n\nCalculate the direction (°T) of the straight line in position B.",
    "feedback": "248°"
  },
  {
    "question": "For climb performance calculations, which altitude is used as a reference to calculate the average TAS through the climb?",
    "feedback": "Two thirds of the climb between take-off and cruise altitudes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The convergency of meridians",
    "feedback": "Is the angular difference between the meridians"
  },
  {
    "question": "When descending on a 3° path with an average rate of descent of 1800 ft/min. from 10000 ft to 2000 ft, you will cover a distance of ....",
    "feedback": "26 NM"
  },
  {
    "question": "On a Direct Mercator chart projection at latitude 30°S, a distance of 80 NM is represented by 3 cm. Using the same chart, 3 cm at latitude 45°N represents ......",
    "feedback": "65 NM"
  }
]